<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Beneath-a-Steel-Sky.svm</path>
		<name>Beneath a Steel Sky</name>
		<desc>In futuristic Australia, there are giant cities owned solely by corporations, separated by a giant wasteland known as The Gap. When Robert Foster's Gap-dwelling tribe is killed by soldiers from Union City who capture him, everything changes for him. After a narrow escape from the helicopter bringing him there as it inexplicably crashes, Robert and his droid Joey must search the decaying city, attempting to befriend both the snobby rich and the frustrated poor as the two attempt to get out of the city, but in the middle of everything they uncover the dark truth about LINC, the bizarre computer which makes the city tick.</desc>
		<image>./images/Beneath-a-Steel-Sky-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19940301T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Revolution Software Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space-Quest-IV-The-Time-Rippers.svm</path>
		<name>Space Quest IV: The Time Rippers</name>
		<desc>Following his humorous adventures in previous game, Roger Wilco is relaxing at his favorite pub somewhere in time and space when heavily armed soldiers enter the room. Carrying a parting message from Roger's old nemesis, Sludge Vohaul, they plan to get rid of the janitorial hero, execution style. That is, until a man with an over-sized hair dryer helps Roger escape through a time rip into the future. Now Roger Wilco has woken up on his home planet, some time in a meta-fictional Space Quest XII. It is a grim, dystopian future: the series has gone to ruin without its hero, and Vohaul rules supreme. Roger must find a way to avoid Vohaul's henchmen, fulfill his destiny, and learn about a few surprises that await him in his own future.</desc>
		<image>./images/Space-Quest-IV-The-Time-Rippers-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Beneath-a-Steel-Sky-1994.svm</path>
		<name>Beneath a Steel Sky (1994)</name>
		<desc>In futuristic Australia, there are giant cities owned solely by corporations, separated by a giant wasteland known as The Gap. When Robert Foster's Gap-dwelling tribe is killed by soldiers from Union City who capture him, everything changes for him. After a narrow escape from the helicopter bringing him there as it inexplicably crashes, Robert and his droid Joey must search the decaying city, attempting to befriend both the snobby rich and the frustrated poor as the two attempt to get out of the city, but in the middle of everything they uncover the dark truth about LINC, the bizarre computer which makes the city tick.</desc>
		<image>./images/Beneath-a-Steel-Sky-1994-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19940301T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Revolution Software Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Broken-Sword-II-The-Smoking-Mirror-1997.svm</path>
		<name>Broken Sword II: The Smoking Mirror (1997)</name>
		<desc>The Smoking Mirror, released in 1997 as the second game in the adventure series Broken Sword, opens with George Stobbart witnessing the kidnapping of his now girlfriend Nico Collard. On his way rescueing Nico George uncovers a secret drug ring that relates to the redemption of a sinister Mayan god. It is also the only game in the series that does not follow the Knights Templar story line.</desc>
		<image>./images/Broken-Sword-II-The-Smoking-Mirror-1997-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19971031T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Revolution Software</developer>
		<publisher>Sony Computer Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Broken-Sword-The-Shadow-of-the-Templars-1996.svm</path>
		<name>Broken Sword: The Shadow of the Templars (1996)</name>
		<desc>George Stobbart is an American tourist on holiday in Paris in the autumn. The story opens with George's quiet coffee at a café rudely interrupted by the explosion of a bomb planted by a man dressed up as a clown. He sets off investigating the explosion and, gradually, he and photo-journalist Nico Collard are drawn into a globe-trotting adventure involving conspiracies, cults and murder, all revolving around the Knights Templar.

The game, which was a critical and commercial success, was released as Circle of Blood in the United States.</desc>
		<image>./images/Broken-Sword-The-Shadow-of-the-Templars-1996-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19960930T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Revolution Software</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Discworld.svm</path>
		<name>Discworld</name>
		<desc>This game is based on the Discworld novel series created by Terry Pratchett. You play Rincewind, a wizard with of little courage or talent in the occult. A dragon is ravaging Ankh-Morpork, the city Rincewind the wizard lives in. The Arch Chancellor sends him to slaigh the beast and you must help him! So you wake up and take your luggage with you (which thinks it's a dog) and search for anything you can use to kill that dragon. Talk to the people of the Discworld (a flat world on which Ankh Morpork lies), though most are useless because they're all mad. And that's exactly the funny part of the game, conversations which lead to nowhere and objects you find on your quest must often be used on such strange things that it's not even logical anymore. This game is meant for gamers who love English humor and like playing an adventure.</desc>
		<image>./images/Discworld-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19951001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Perfect Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Psygnosis</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Discworld-II-Missing-Presumed.svm</path>
		<name>Discworld II: Missing Presumed...!?</name>
		<desc>Discworld II: Missing Presumed...!? (Discworld II: Mortality Bytes! in North America) is the second point-and-click adventure game based on Terry Pratchett's series of fantasy novels set on the mythical Discworld. The game was developed and produced in 1996 by Perfect Entertainment for the PC, and ported in 1997 for the PlayStation and Sega Saturn. It was published by Psygnosis for the PC and PlayStation, and by Sega for the Saturn (only in Europe).

In Discworld II the player controls Rincewind the "wizzard" (voiced by Eric Idle, as in the previous game) who has been burdened with the task of coercing Death out of his impromptu retirement and back into his regular duties. The plot borrows from a number of Discworld books, most notably Reaper Man, Moving Pictures and Lords and Ladies.

It all begins in a quiet Ankh-Morpork street, where Rincewind and The Librarian inexplicably fail to die from a nearby cart-bomb explosion. The odd event is not shared by them alone however: occurrences of the newly dead re-awakening and disturbing the populace are being reported all over the city, prompting the Archchancellor of Unseen University to halt his usual activities of feasting and merrymaking, and to take charge of the situation. Much to Rincewind's despair, the entirety of this process involves appointing him to the task of finding Death and convincing him to resume his work.</desc>
		<image>./images/Discworld-II-Missing-Presumed-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19961130T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Perfect Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Psygnosis</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Drascula-The-Vampire-Strikes-Back.svm</path>
		<name>Drascula: The Vampire Strikes Back</name>
		<desc>Drascula: The Vampire Strikes Back is the only game known that uses the drascula engine. It is an old Spanish 2D classic point &amp; click style adventure with tons of humor and an easy interface.

You are John Hacker, a common guy that gets to meet a gorgeous blond girl, who gets kidnapped by the count and embark on a fun yet dangerous quest to rescue her.</desc>
		<image>./images/Drascula-The-Vampire-Strikes-Back-image.jpg</image>
		<developer>Alcachofa Soft</developer>
		<publisher>Midas Interactive Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Flight-of-the-Amazon-Queen.svm</path>
		<name>Flight of the Amazon Queen</name>
		<desc>Flight of the Amazon Queen follows a pilot for hire named Joe King who is hired to fly a famous actress to her next job, but ends up in a lightning storm and crashes deep in the Amazon Jungle. In the jungle, Joe uncovers a plot by a mad scientist to take over the world by creating an army of dinosaur women created from Amazon women.</desc>
		<image>./images/Flight-of-the-Amazon-Queen-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950306T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Interactive Binary Illusions</developer>
		<publisher>Warner Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Full-Throttle.svm</path>
		<name>Full Throttle</name>
		<desc>The story is set in a dystopian future where motorized vehicles are giving way to anti-gravitational hovercrafts. A hardened biker named Ben is the leader of a motorcycle gang called the Polecats. As his gang rides down Highway 9, they come across an expensive white hovercraft limousine. Ben, in the lead, unceremoniously drives over the limousine, crushing the hood ornament. Unknown to the gang, the limo belongs to Malcolm Corley, the CEO and founder of the last domestic motorcycle manufacturer in the country, Corley Motors. Intrigued and impressed, Corley demands his driver catch up to the gang.</desc>
		<image>./images/Full-Throttle-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19950430T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>LucasArts</developer>
		<publisher>LucasArts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gobliiins.svm</path>
		<name>Gobliiins</name>
		<desc>Gobliiins is an adventure game where the player controls a team of three goblins: Oups, Ignatius and Asgard (Hooter, Dwayne, and BoBo in the US release) to find four magic components. A voodoo doll has turned their king Angoulafre mad and by collecting the components they can track down Niak the Wizard, the only one who can put things right. The player needs to solve various puzzles by combining the different skills of the three goblins. It's possible switch between them and control them separately. Most of the puzzles are based on coordinated actions. One can cast powerful but erratic spells, another can collect and use objects, and the last can hit things. Action icons are activated at the bottom of the screen. The game takes in 22 landscapes, each of which has puzzles which must be cleared. The characters have limited energy, which can be sapped by traps.</desc>
		<image>./images/Gobliiins-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Coktel Vision</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gobliins-II-The-Prince-Buffoon.svm</path>
		<name>Gobliins 2: The Prince Buffoon</name>
		<desc>The second in the series of adventure-puzzle games. In this installation, you only have two imps to control instead of three.

Someone has kidnapped the prince and it's up to you and two hilarious sidekicks, Winkle and Fingus, to rescue him. Winkle is a reckless jokester, while Fingus is careful and has a gift for solving puzzles. Luckily, they're blessed with extraordinary vitality. In other words, they never die. That'll sure come in handy when you're up against Wily Wizard's traps, maniacal monsters, and twisted and perplexing puzzles.</desc>
		<image>./images/Gobliins-II-The-Prince-Buffoon-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Coktel Vision</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre></genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Goblins-Quest-III.svm</path>
		<name>Goblins Quest 3</name>
		<desc>It is said that there is a mysterious labyrinth harboring great secrets that might fulfill the wishes of those who discover them. Two countries respectively ruled by Queen Xina and King Bodd have been competing over the right to explore the labyrinth. However, strange events started happening one after the other: the guardian of the labyrinth died, his daughter disappeared, and King Bodd apparently fell under some sort of a curse. A goblin reporter named Blount get caught in the midst of these events as he attempts to interview the queen and the king. As if that weren't enough, Blount also gets bitten by a werewolf and falls in love, and must find a way to deal with both predicaments.

Goblins Quest is the third entry in the Gobliiins series. Like its predecessors, it is a puzzle adventure game with the emphasis on solving complex tasks confined to smaller areas rather than on exploration. Most levels occupy more than one screen and allow limited navigation between different areas. As the reduction of the title to a single "i" implies, this installment only features one controllable goblin. However, at various points of the game Blount will require assistance from other player-controlled characters such as Chump the parrot, Ooya the magician, and Fulbert the snake. In addition, Blount's own spontaneous transformation into a werewolf may affect the solution of some puzzles. The hero will also undergo a few other mutations and drastically change his size during the course of the game.</desc>
		<image>./images/Goblins-Quest-III-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Coktel Vision</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre></genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gold-Rush.svm</path>
		<name>Gold Rush!</name>
		<desc>In Gold Rush!, Jerrod Wilson (the player) receives a letter from his long-lost brother (who fled the city years before when was hastily accused and convicted of a crime he didn't commit) asking him to join in Sacramento, California. If that's not enough for Jerrod sell everything and give his hometown Brooklyn a fond adieu, under the stamp was one of the first nuggets of Californian gold seen in the Atlantic shores of the United States. So, Jerrod bids farewell to his peaceful life as a newspaper editor, and becomes a fore-runner in the the great Gold Rush of 1849, hoping to find his brother and "strike gold" (literally).

Released late into the lifespan of Sierra's AGI engine, Gold Rush! features some tricks not seen before the more advanced SCI engine, such as enlarged characters, but it is best known for the three routes available to reach California: by land, travel by boat to reach the Atlantic shore of Panama, cross the isthmus, and then get a second boat in the Pacific shore, or making the dangerous all-boat trip by Cape Horn. Each route has it's dangers: Cholera might strike as you make your way across the Northern states or your boat might sink.. As usual with Sierra adventures, instant killing happens if the player is careless, but will also happen at random. Other important (and innovative) concept is the game being timed. If Jerrod takes too long to leave Brooklyn, passages to California increase in price, and his house devalues.</desc>
		<image>./images/Gold-Rush-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Hugo-II-Whodunit.svm</path>
		<name>Hugo II: Whodunit?</name>
		<desc>Hugo II: Whodunit? is the second game in the Hugo adventure game series.

Hugo and his wife, Penelope, arrive to stay at the mansion that belongs to Hugo's Great Uncle Horace. Penelope falls asleep in the bedroom, while Hugo accidentally finds a bookcase passage and is locked in a secret room. Penelope wakes up, only to witness Uncle Horace's murder through the keyhole. The player controls Penelope (and later, briefly, Hugo) and must solve the murder.

Much like its predecessor, Hugo's House of Horrors, Hugo II: Whodunit? is an adventure game in the style of Sierra's AGI games. The player moves Penelope with arrow keys and types in commands on the bottom of the screen.</desc>
		<image>./images/Hugo-II-Whodunit-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Grey Design</developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Hugo-III-Jungle-of-Doom.svm</path>
		<name>Hugo III: Jungle of Doom</name>
		<desc>Hugo III: Jungle of Doom is the third and final installment in the EGA adventure series Hugo. The game features the existing engine in previous Hugo games along with some new features. These include a turbo button, and a "hints" feature. In this game Hugo and his girlfriend Penolope crash in a jungle somewhere in South America and she is soon bitten by a poisonous snake. As Hugo you venture through the jungle, confront a witch doctor and try to find the "pool of life". The Hugo series goes on to become a 3d first person shooter, Nitemare-3D.</desc>
		<image>./images/Hugo-III-Jungle-of-Doom-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920220T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Grey Design</developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Hugos-House-of-Horrors.svm</path>
		<name>Hugo's House of Horrors</name>
		<desc>You are Hugo and you have to save your girlfriend, who had went to babysit a baby in a haunted house. Gameplay is similar to traditional Sierra-style adventures.</desc>
		<image>./images/Hugos-House-of-Horrors-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Grey Design</developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./I-Have-No-Mouth-and-I-Must-Scream.svm</path>
		<name>I Have No Mouth, and I Must Scream</name>
		<desc>The game is based on a collection of short stories by Harlan Ellison. After the Cold War, the computers of the USA, Russia and China take over the world and wipe out almost the entire human race. The Allied Mastercomputer (called AM) holds the last five humans as prisoners to torture them. Any of them has to face his or her past in a virtual adventure AM has designed for them. There they encounter their fears and weaknesses.

The player can choose which of the protagonists he wants to be but in fact he has to complete all of the six stories in order to solve the game. There are different ways of completing the game depending on the humanity the player shows.

The voiceacting features Harlan Ellison as AM.</desc>
		<image>./images/I-Have-No-Mouth-and-I-Must-Scream-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19951231T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>The Dreamers Guild</developer>
		<publisher>Cyberdreams</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Indiana-Jones-and-the-Fate-of-Atlantis.svm</path>
		<name>Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis</name>
		<desc>Fate of Atlantis has the player explore environments and interact with objects and characters by using commands constructed with predetermined verbs. It features three unique paths to select, influencing story development, gameplay and puzzles.</desc>
		<image>./images/Indiana-Jones-and-the-Fate-of-Atlantis-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19920615T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>LucasArts</developer>
		<publisher>LucasArts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Indiana-Jones-and-the-Last-Crusade.svm</path>
		<name>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</name>
		<desc>It is 1938 and adventurer Indiana Jones is joined by his father on this quest, preventing Adolf Hitler from capturing the Holy Grail. He will have to deal with Nazi guards, the Luftwaffe and enemy spies as he tries to stop the tyrannical Nazi leader.

The Graphic Adventure uses the same SCUMM gameplay system as the previous Maniac Mansion. Most of the screen is used for a visual rendition of the current scene. At the bottom of the screen are words, which can be clicked on using the mouse to activate their functions. For example, objects can be picked up, used, pushed or pulled, and turned on and off. Most locations are from the movie, but some further scenes are added.

In keeping with Indiana's action-man persona, the game also features pure action scenes. Unlike most Lucasfilm adventures, you can die.

Two PC versions of the game were released, one with 16 color EGA graphics, and one with 256 color VGA graphics.</desc>
		<image>./images/Indiana-Jones-and-the-Last-Crusade-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19890702T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasfilm Games</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasfilm Games</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Inherit-the-Earth-Quest-for-the-Orb.svm</path>
		<name>Inherit the Earth: Quest for the Orb</name>
		<image>./images/Inherit-the-Earth-Quest-for-the-Orb-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>The Dreamers Guild</developer>
		<publisher>New World Computing</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kings-Quest-II-Romancing-the-Throne-1985.svm</path>
		<name>King's Quest II: Romancing the Throne (1985)</name>
		<desc>The Magic Mirror shows King Graham a vision about a beautiful woman, Valanice, imprisoned on the top of an ivory tower. Being charmed by her, he is teleported to the world of Kolyma to rescue her. There he must travel through sea, air, and even death to gain the keys that unlock the three doors to the enchanted island where Hagatha the witch has imprisoned Valanice.</desc>
		<image>./images/Kings-Quest-II-Romancing-the-Throne-1985-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19850501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kings-Quest-III-To-Heir-Is-Human-1986.svm</path>
		<name>King's Quest III: To Heir is Human (1986)</name>
		<desc>Become Gwydion, young slave to the evil wizard manannan of Llewdor. Discover the wizard's secret spells and use his magic to free yourself from his thrall. Embark upon a dangerous voyage to another land. Scale snowy peaks and brave a terrible monster to free a kingdom from it's ravages.</desc>
		<image>./images/Kings-Quest-III-To-Heir-Is-Human-1986-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19861101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kings-Quest-IV-The-Perils-of-Rosella.svm</path>
		<name>King's Quest IV: The Perils of Rosella</name>
		<desc>King Graham and Queen Valanice were glad to have their children back. Graham thinks that it is time to pass onto them his old adventurers' hat. When he throws it across the room, he suffers a heart attack and collapses on the floor, and he is carried off to bed. The only way that Graham's health can be restored is by retrieving the magic fruit in the faraway land of Tamir. A beautiful fairy called Genesta offers Rosella the chance to be transported to the land, and find the fruit. But once she gets transported, she cannot be sent back unless she helps the fairy regain her talisman that was stolen by the evil witch, Lolotte.</desc>
		<image>./images/Kings-Quest-IV-The-Perils-of-Rosella-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880816T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kings-Quest-V-Absence-Makes-the-Heart-Go-Yonder.svm</path>
		<name>King's Quest V: Absence Makes the Heart Go Yonder!</name>
		<desc>Dark powers summon a cold wind from the north. The terrifying gust surrounds Sir Graham's castle, and mysteriously sweeps his fortress and family into the prison of oblivion. It's a bitter omen that chills the bones of every man, woman and child in the once peaceful Kingdom of Daventry. Who or what is responsible for this royal theft, and the misery that ravages the heart of Daventry? Has the ruthless wizard Manannan cast another evil spell? Or are the Black Forest Witch and the unforgiving Ice Queen using sinister powers to promote their wicked cause? Only you can answer these questions, as you assume the role of Sir Graham, then set forth on an adventure that will test your intelligence, challenge your skill and rip your courage to shreds.</desc>
		<image>./images/Kings-Quest-V-Absence-Makes-the-Heart-Go-Yonder-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19901109T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kings-Quest-VI-Heir-Today-Gone-Tomorrow.svm</path>
		<name>King's Quest VI: Heir Today, Gone Tomorrow</name>
		<desc>For months Prince Alexander of Daventry has shut himself away from the world, thinking only of Princess Cassima, who he met while imprisoned in the previous game. Eventually he can take it no longer, and he hires a ship to search for the Land of the Green Isles located on the edge of the world. After months of searching he finally sets sight upon the island kingdom, only for a freak storm to strike the ship, destroying it and leaving him the only survivor. His troubles are far from over, however, as he soon finds out that the King and Queen have passed away, the Greens Isles are on the brink of war, and his beloved Princess Cassima may even be held prisoner by the royal vizier.</desc>
		<image>./images/Kings-Quest-VI-Heir-Today-Gone-Tomorrow-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920930T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kings-Quest-Quest-for-the-Crown-1990.svm</path>
		<name>King's Quest: Quest for the Crown (1990)</name>
		<desc>Roberta Williams' King's Quest I: Quest for the Crown is a remake of King's Quest. It uses Sierra's 16-color SCI game interpreter, making it visually similar to the series' fourth installment, with more detailed EGA full-screen graphics and optional mouse support, while retaining text-based input and interaction. This version also has a musical score that supports sound cards, as opposed to the speaker-only output of the original release.

Several changes have been made to the game's locations and script. A few new characters appear in the remake, and some of the conversations feature additional lines. A number of puzzles have slightly different solutions, and some objects are found in different places than they were in the original version.</desc>
		<image>./images/Kings-Quest-Quest-for-the-Crown-1990-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19900201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Leisure-Suit-Larry-II-Goes-Looking-for-Love-in-Several-Wrong-Places.svm</path>
		<name>Leisure Suit Larry II: Goes Looking for Love (In Several Wrong Places)</name>
		<desc>Leisure Suit Larry Goes Looking for Love (In Several Wrong Places) is the second game in Al Lowe's Leisure Suit Larry series. Continuing the plot of the previous game, the swinging single Larry Laffer has finally found his true love and is happily living with her. Right? Wrong!.. Because Larry is mercilessly thrown out by his great love and is left all alone, penniless, and womanless, in Los Angeles. Accidentally, Larry comes into contact with KGB agents who will pursue him all over the globe from now on. And there is also the evil doctor Noontonyt plotting evil schemes on a remote tropical island... Looks like Larry will have to forget about his women-related problems for now... or is it so?

The second game in the series introduces an improved engine (allowing for full-screen graphics and mouse control for movement). As opposed to the first game, which relied on exploration of one large area, the sequel has a more linear progression, the player being continuously taken to new locations as dictated by the plot. There are less puzzles in this installment than in the previous game; however, the number of ways to die has increased, danger awaiting Larry in most places he visits.</desc>
		<image>./images/Leisure-Suit-Larry-II-Goes-Looking-for-Love-in-Several-Wrong-Places-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19881027T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Leisure-Suit-Larry-III-Passionate-Patti-in-Pursuit-of-the-Pulsating-Pectorals.svm</path>
		<name>Leisure Suit Larry III: Passionate Patti in Pursuit of the Pulsating Pectorals</name>
		<desc>Passionate Patti in Pursuit of the Pulsating Pectorals! is the third game in Al Lowe's Leisure Suit Larry series. Larry Laffer has finally found the woman of his dreams, and can happily live with her together on the beautiful tropical island... until he gets thrown out of the house by his wife. His boss, who happens to be his (now ex-) father-in-law, fires him. Larry is all alone, without a woman, without a job, on an island that has long ceased to be a "tropical paradise" and is exploited by entertainers, lawyers, and alike. But never despair! Dressed in his irresistible leisure suit, Larry is about to conquer the world (or at least its female population) anew. Watch out, fairer sex, because Larry is back to his swinging self!</desc>
		<image>./images/Leisure-Suit-Larry-III-Passionate-Patti-in-Pursuit-of-the-Pulsating-Pectorals-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Leisure-Suit-Larry-in-the-Land-of-the-Lounge-Lizards-1991.svm</path>
		<name>Leisure Suit Larry in the Land of the Lounge Lizards (1991)</name>
		<desc>Leisure Suit Larry 1: In the Land of the Lounge Lizards is a remake of the first game in the Leisure Suit Larry series. It introduces a new interface. Instead of typing commands, the player performs the desired actions by choosing appropriate icons, and then clicking on objects on the screen to interact with them. The graphics are now 256 color VGA. There is also much more music than in the original version, and it supports more advanced sound formats.</desc>
		<image>./images/Leisure-Suit-Larry-in-the-Land-of-the-Lounge-Lizards-1991-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Leisure-Suit-Larry-V-Passionate-Patti-Does-a-Little-Undercover-Work.svm</path>
		<name>Leisure Suit Larry V: Passionate Patti Does a Little Undercover Work</name>
		<desc>Passionate Patti Does a Little Undercover Work! is (despite the number) the fourth game in Al Lowe's Leisure Suit Larry series. The middle-aged would-be-womanizer Larry Laffer fell off a boat during a cruise and sustained amnesia, forgetting how he and his sweetheart Patti got separated, how Larry got a job in LA, how Patti got a job with the FBI, and what happened in (the never released) Larry 4. Now Larry and Patti are working independently on two cases that are connected to each other, even though the heroes aren't aware of that. Larry's new bosses are involved in shady business, while Patti agrees to take a break from her career as a performing pianist and become an undercover agent. Will the two be together ever again?</desc>
		<image>./images/Leisure-Suit-Larry-V-Passionate-Patti-Does-a-Little-Undercover-Work-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Leisure-Suit-Larry-VI-Shape-Up-or-Slip-Out-1994.svm</path>
		<name>Leisure Suit Larry VI: Shape Up or Slip Out! (1994)</name>
		<desc>Shape Up or Slip Out! is the fifth game in Al Lowe's Leisure Suit Larry series. All the events from the previous games are forgotten. Larry is once again single, and again his goal is to capture the interest of various ladies. By sheer coincidence, Larry finds himself on a TV Game Show called "Stallions". He wins a weekend at the Spa Resort, La Costa Lotta. Naturally, there are some beautiful women in the spa who are just dreaming about such a wonderful, handsome man as Larry! Uh... or is it really so? It is the player's goal to find out!

This instalment focuses more on conversations with women and puzzles than on the storyline. The entire game is spent at La Costa Lotta. There are plenty of traditional inventory-based puzzles to solve in the game. Larry can die, but the player is allowed to try again every time that happens, without the need to restore a saved game. This is also the first Larry game with SVGA graphics, and voice-overs in the CD version.</desc>
		<image>./images/Leisure-Suit-Larry-VI-Shape-Up-or-Slip-Out-1994-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Loom-1992.svm</path>
		<name>Loom (1992)</name>
		<desc>The Age of the Great Guilds has arrived. Communities and states comprised of people united by a common trade were created. The Guild of Weavers has achieved such mastery in their trade that they discovered the secret of weaving the very fabric of reality. They were treated with suspicion by other guilds, who eventually accused them of practicing witchcraft and banned them to a secluded island, which they called Loom.

Bobbin Threadbare is a young man from the Guild of Weavers. He is outcast from the guild and blamed for the lack of prosperity in recent times, though he does not know why. On his seventeenth birthday he is summoned by the Elders of the guild, who intend to decide his fate. However, shortly thereafter all the inhabitants of the village except Bobbin are turned into swans. Bobbin finds out that he is the child of the Great Loom, found by Lady Cygna, who tried to use the loom's powers to save the guild. Bobbin's stepmother Dame Hetchel teaches him the art of weaving magical drafts, and Bobbin embarks on a journey to find the lost flock, and the answers to his questions.

Loom is an adventure game that sets itself apart from other titles in the genre through its unique gameplay system: the player character does not carry items around, but rather manipulates objects through the use of spells (called "drafts" in the game). The drafts themselves are woven by playing magical notes on a special instrument called "distaff". All the puzzles in the game are solved by learning and correctly applying these drafts.

Each draft is a sequence of four notes within one octave. The player learns new drafts by exploring the environment and interacting with it through a simple point-and-click interface. Once a draft has been learned, it may be applied in a different situation in order to solve a problem. Drafts range from simple general actions (such as opening) to more specific and complex commands, e.g. turning straw into gold. Drafts can also be "reversed", i.e. played backwards, in order to execute the opposite action (for example, closing something instead of opening). As the game progresses Bobbin learns to play higher notes on the distaff, allowing him to access more drafts.

The game features three difficulty levels, differentiating them by changing the way the interface works. The easiest level displays names of the notes as well as marking the correspondent areas on the distaff; Standard level features the distaff with the marks at the bottom of the screen, but no written notes; whereas Expert does not display the marks at all, requiring the player to memorize and play the drafts by ear.

The CD DOS version of the game has enhanced 256-color graphics, audio tracks, and full voice acting. However, it also removes a few close-up scenes and conversations. The FM Towns version preserves these scenes and includes similar graphical and musical enhancements, but has no voice acting.</desc>
		<image>./images/Loom-1992-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasarts</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasarts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Loom-FMTOWNS-0-standard.svm</path>
		<name>Loom (FM-TOWNS) 0-standard</name>
		<desc>The Age of the Great Guilds has arrived. Communities and states comprised of people united by a common trade were created. The Guild of Weavers has achieved such mastery in their trade that they discovered the secret of weaving the very fabric of reality. They were treated with suspicion by other guilds, who eventually accused them of practicing witchcraft and banned them to a secluded island, which they called Loom.

Bobbin Threadbare is a young man from the Guild of Weavers. He is outcast from the guild and blamed for the lack of prosperity in recent times, though he does not know why. On his seventeenth birthday he is summoned by the Elders of the guild, who intend to decide his fate. However, shortly thereafter all the inhabitants of the village except Bobbin are turned into swans. Bobbin finds out that he is the child of the Great Loom, found by Lady Cygna, who tried to use the loom's powers to save the guild. Bobbin's stepmother Dame Hetchel teaches him the art of weaving magical drafts, and Bobbin embarks on a journey to find the lost flock, and the answers to his questions.

Loom is an adventure game that sets itself apart from other titles in the genre through its unique gameplay system: the player character does not carry items around, but rather manipulates objects through the use of spells (called "drafts" in the game). The drafts themselves are woven by playing magical notes on a special instrument called "distaff". All the puzzles in the game are solved by learning and correctly applying these drafts.

Each draft is a sequence of four notes within one octave. The player learns new drafts by exploring the environment and interacting with it through a simple point-and-click interface. Once a draft has been learned, it may be applied in a different situation in order to solve a problem. Drafts range from simple general actions (such as opening) to more specific and complex commands, e.g. turning straw into gold. Drafts can also be "reversed", i.e. played backwards, in order to execute the opposite action (for example, closing something instead of opening). As the game progresses Bobbin learns to play higher notes on the distaff, allowing him to access more drafts.

The game features three difficulty levels, differentiating them by changing the way the interface works. The easiest level displays names of the notes as well as marking the correspondent areas on the distaff; Standard level features the distaff with the marks at the bottom of the screen, but no written notes; whereas Expert does not display the marks at all, requiring the player to memorize and play the drafts by ear.

The CD DOS version of the game has enhanced 256-color graphics, audio tracks, and full voice acting. However, it also removes a few close-up scenes and conversations. The FM Towns version preserves these scenes and includes similar graphical and musical enhancements, but has no voice acting.</desc>
		<image>./images/Loom-FMTOWNS-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasarts</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasarts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Loom-FMTOWNS-1-novice.svm</path>
		<name>Loom (FM-TOWNS) 1-novice</name>
		<desc>The Age of the Great Guilds has arrived. Communities and states comprised of people united by a common trade were created. The Guild of Weavers has achieved such mastery in their trade that they discovered the secret of weaving the very fabric of reality. They were treated with suspicion by other guilds, who eventually accused them of practicing witchcraft and banned them to a secluded island, which they called Loom.

Bobbin Threadbare is a young man from the Guild of Weavers. He is outcast from the guild and blamed for the lack of prosperity in recent times, though he does not know why. On his seventeenth birthday he is summoned by the Elders of the guild, who intend to decide his fate. However, shortly thereafter all the inhabitants of the village except Bobbin are turned into swans. Bobbin finds out that he is the child of the Great Loom, found by Lady Cygna, who tried to use the loom's powers to save the guild. Bobbin's stepmother Dame Hetchel teaches him the art of weaving magical drafts, and Bobbin embarks on a journey to find the lost flock, and the answers to his questions.

Loom is an adventure game that sets itself apart from other titles in the genre through its unique gameplay system: the player character does not carry items around, but rather manipulates objects through the use of spells (called "drafts" in the game). The drafts themselves are woven by playing magical notes on a special instrument called "distaff". All the puzzles in the game are solved by learning and correctly applying these drafts.

Each draft is a sequence of four notes within one octave. The player learns new drafts by exploring the environment and interacting with it through a simple point-and-click interface. Once a draft has been learned, it may be applied in a different situation in order to solve a problem. Drafts range from simple general actions (such as opening) to more specific and complex commands, e.g. turning straw into gold. Drafts can also be "reversed", i.e. played backwards, in order to execute the opposite action (for example, closing something instead of opening). As the game progresses Bobbin learns to play higher notes on the distaff, allowing him to access more drafts.

The game features three difficulty levels, differentiating them by changing the way the interface works. The easiest level displays names of the notes as well as marking the correspondent areas on the distaff; Standard level features the distaff with the marks at the bottom of the screen, but no written notes; whereas Expert does not display the marks at all, requiring the player to memorize and play the drafts by ear.

The CD DOS version of the game has enhanced 256-color graphics, audio tracks, and full voice acting. However, it also removes a few close-up scenes and conversations. The FM Towns version preserves these scenes and includes similar graphical and musical enhancements, but has no voice acting.</desc>
		<image>./images/Loom-FMTOWNS-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasarts</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasarts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Loom-FMTOWNS-2-expert.svm</path>
		<name>Loom (FM-TOWNS) 2-expert</name>
		<desc>The Age of the Great Guilds has arrived. Communities and states comprised of people united by a common trade were created. The Guild of Weavers has achieved such mastery in their trade that they discovered the secret of weaving the very fabric of reality. They were treated with suspicion by other guilds, who eventually accused them of practicing witchcraft and banned them to a secluded island, which they called Loom.

Bobbin Threadbare is a young man from the Guild of Weavers. He is outcast from the guild and blamed for the lack of prosperity in recent times, though he does not know why. On his seventeenth birthday he is summoned by the Elders of the guild, who intend to decide his fate. However, shortly thereafter all the inhabitants of the village except Bobbin are turned into swans. Bobbin finds out that he is the child of the Great Loom, found by Lady Cygna, who tried to use the loom's powers to save the guild. Bobbin's stepmother Dame Hetchel teaches him the art of weaving magical drafts, and Bobbin embarks on a journey to find the lost flock, and the answers to his questions.

Loom is an adventure game that sets itself apart from other titles in the genre through its unique gameplay system: the player character does not carry items around, but rather manipulates objects through the use of spells (called "drafts" in the game). The drafts themselves are woven by playing magical notes on a special instrument called "distaff". All the puzzles in the game are solved by learning and correctly applying these drafts.

Each draft is a sequence of four notes within one octave. The player learns new drafts by exploring the environment and interacting with it through a simple point-and-click interface. Once a draft has been learned, it may be applied in a different situation in order to solve a problem. Drafts range from simple general actions (such as opening) to more specific and complex commands, e.g. turning straw into gold. Drafts can also be "reversed", i.e. played backwards, in order to execute the opposite action (for example, closing something instead of opening). As the game progresses Bobbin learns to play higher notes on the distaff, allowing him to access more drafts.

The game features three difficulty levels, differentiating them by changing the way the interface works. The easiest level displays names of the notes as well as marking the correspondent areas on the distaff; Standard level features the distaff with the marks at the bottom of the screen, but no written notes; whereas Expert does not display the marks at all, requiring the player to memorize and play the drafts by ear.

The CD DOS version of the game has enhanced 256-color graphics, audio tracks, and full voice acting. However, it also removes a few close-up scenes and conversations. The FM Towns version preserves these scenes and includes similar graphical and musical enhancements, but has no voice acting.</desc>
		<image>./images/Loom-FMTOWNS-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasarts</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasarts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Lure-of-the-Temptress.svm</path>
		<name>Lure of the Temptress</name>
		<desc>Lure of the Temptress is an Adventure game, developed by Revolution Software and published by Konami, which was released in 1992.</desc>
		<image>./images/Lure-of-the-Temptress-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.2</rating>
		<releasedate>19920412T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Revolution Software</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Manhunter-II-San-Francisco.svm</path>
		<name>Manhunter II: San Francisco</name>
		<desc>Picking up immediately where Manhunter: New York left off, Manhunter 2: San Francisco has the player crash-landing their stolen ship in the City by the Bay after trying unsuccessfully to keep up with enigmatic serial killer Phil. Left with no alternatives, the player assumes the identity of a local Manhunter and solves more crimes for the alien Orbs while searching for Phil and working for the local human resistance.

Manhunter 2 presents the same urban decay and oppressive alien invader regime as visualized in the original, this time using streets and landmarks from the Bay Area. The Golden Gate Bridge, Coit Tower, Alcatraz prison, and the TransAmerica Pyramid all receive alien makeovers. New puzzles, new characters, and new investigations await as the player tracks Phil by his string of strangled corpses.

All concepts and gameplay elements from Manhunter: New York return. The player again uses the MAD tracking device to follow suspects provided by the alien Orbs and uses clues found through first-person location investigation to discover the suspects' name. Occasional arcade sequences bring mixed challenges, and though they cannot be skipped, a new difficulty option has been implemented. The same point-and-click gameplay (no typing required) is used to navigate the game world.</desc>
		<image>./images/Manhunter-II-San-Francisco-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Evryware</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Manhunter-New-York.svm</path>
		<name>Manhunter: New York</name>
		<desc>The Earth has been invaded by the Orb Alliance, and a tightly restricted regime instituted for the humans that remain. Brown monk robes are the only garments allowed, speaking is a capital offense, and every human has been implanted with a tracking chip recording their every move. To track down criminals, the Orbs enlist "Manhunters" - humans given access to advanced technology and selected to be a combination of police officers and bounty hunters. The player controls one such Manhunter as he unravels a conspiracy inside the decaying heart of the New York ruins, and a mysterious serial killer on the loose.

Each chapter begins with the Orbs assigning the player's nameless Manhunter with a crime (such as murder) or target to investigate. The player gains leads through the use of the "MAD" computer, which displays the logs of all civilian movement in an area in an overhead map view. By starting with the victim and following the people who encountered him that day, the player can then go to a first-person investigation view at various New York landmarks to find clues to the suspect's identity. At the end of the day, the player must report the correct name of their suspect to the Orbs.

Manhunter uses a modified version of Sierra's AGI interpreter, with a rudimentary point-and-click interface used to locate and uncover clues at the investigation sites. At various times throughout the investigation, the player will also have to directly control the Manhunter in arcade-style challenges, like dodging gang attacks or throwing knives between a bar patron's fingers.</desc>
		<image>./images/Manhunter-New-York-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Evryware</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Maniac-Mansion-1989.svm</path>
		<name>Maniac Mansion (1989)</name>
		<desc>Maniac Mansion is a graphic adventure game developed and published by Lucasfilm Games. Initially released for the Commodore 64 and Apple II, it was Lucasfilm's foray into video game publishing. The game follows teenager Dave Miller as he ventures into a mansion and attempts to rescue his girlfriend from an evil mad scientist, whose family has been controlled by a sentient meteor that crashed near the mansion 20 years earlier. The player uses a point-and-click interface to guide Dave and two of his friends through the mansion while avoiding its dangerous inhabitants and solving puzzles.

The Enhanced PC version was released in 1989, for the PC. Gamewise, it's nearly a carbon copy of the original, but with two big improvements which really make a difference: vastly superior graphics and the possibility to save your game on 10 different slots. I think this is the all around best version, and if you want to play Maniac Mansion for the first time, by all means, look for this one. The screenshots used to illustrate this website come from this version.</desc>
		<image>./images/Maniac-Mansion-1989-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasfilm Games</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasfilm Games</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Maniac-Mansion-II-Day-of-the-Tentacle-1993.svm</path>
		<name>Maniac Mansion II: Day of the Tentacle (1993)</name>
		<desc>Five years after the events of Maniac Mansion, Purple Tentacle—a mutant monster and lab assistant created by mad scientist Dr. Fred Edison—drinks toxic sludge from Dr. Fred's laboratory. The sludge causes him to grow a pair of flipper-like arms and develop a vastly increased intelligence and a thirst for global domination. Dr. Fred plans to resolve the issue by killing Purple Tentacle and his harmless, friendly brother Green Tentacle, but before he can Green Tentacle sends a plea of help to his old friend, the nerd Bernard Bernoulli. Bernard travels to the Edison family motel with his two housemates, deranged medical student Laverne and roadie Hoagie, and frees the tentacles. Purple Tentacle escapes to resume his quest to take over the world.</desc>
		<image>./images/Maniac-Mansion-II-Day-of-the-Tentacle-1993-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19930601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasarts</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasarts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Monkey-Island-II-LeChucks-Revenge-1991.svm</path>
		<name>Monkey Island II: LeChuck's Revenge (1991)</name>
		<desc>LeChuck's Revenge is set in the fictional Tri-Island Area of the Caribbean, several months after The Secret of Monkey Island. The game opens in medias res as Guybrush Threepwood hangs on a rope above a hole, narrating to Elaine Marley on a separate rope the events that led to this situation. The flashback sequence starts on Scabb Island and constitutes most of the playable game's setting. During it, Guybrush also visits Phatt Island, Booty Island, and Dinky Island, voyaging on two different pirate ships.</desc>
		<image>./images/Monkey-Island-II-LeChucks-Revenge-1991-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>1</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>LucasArts</developer>
		<publisher>LucasArts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Monkey-Island-III-The-Curse-of-Monkey-Island.svm</path>
		<name>Monkey Island III: The Curse of Monkey Island</name>
		<desc>This third installment in the Monkey Island franchise is, like its predecessors, a humorous puzzle-solving adventure game. The game features cartoon-style SVGA graphics and (for the first time in the series) voice-overs for all the conversations. The interface no longer involves a list of verbs that occupies a part of the screen; instead the player chooses first the object to interact with, then the action from a menu that appears. Like the second game, The Curse of Monkey Island has two difficulty levels.</desc>
		<image>./images/Monkey-Island-III-The-Curse-of-Monkey-Island-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19971031T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>LucasArts</developer>
		<publisher>LucasArts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Monkey-Island-The-Secret-of-Monkey-Island-1990.svm</path>
		<name>Monkey Island: The Secret of Monkey Island (1990)</name>
		<desc>The game begins on the Caribbean island of Mêlée, where a youth named Guybrush Threepwood wants to be a pirate. He seeks out the Pirate Leaders, who set him three challenges to prove himself a pirate: defeat Carla, the island's swordmaster in insult swordfighting, steal a statue from the Governor's mansion, and find buried treasure.
Along the way he meets several interesting characters, including Stan the used boat salesman, Meathook (a fellow with hooks on both hands), a prisoner named Otis, the three men of low moral fiber and, most significantly, the gorgeous Governor Elaine Marley. The ghost pirate LeChuck, however, has been in love with Elaine since his living days. While Guybrush is busy, LeChuck's ghost crew abduct her, taking her to Monkey Island. Guybrush gathers a crew (Carla, Meathook, and Otis), buys a boat, and sets out to find the mysterious island and free Elaine.
When Guybrush finally reaches Monkey Island, he explores it and discovers a band of cannibals and a strange hermit named Herman Toothrot. After he helps the cannibals recover a lost voodoo ingredient (a magical root), they provide him with a seltzer bottle filled with "voodoo root elixir" that can destroy ghosts. However, when Guybrush goes after LeChuck, he is told that LeChuck went to Mêlée Island to marry Elaine.
Guybrush returns to Mêlée and goes to the church to prevent the wedding. When he arrives at the church wedding, he realises that Elaine had her own plan to escape. Guybrush loses the elixir and LeChuck starts beating him, until they arrive at the ship emporium where he finds a bottle of root beer. Substituting root beer for the lost ghost-fighting elixir, he sprays LeChuck and the ghost pirate is destroyed. With LeChuck defeated, Guybrush and Elaine enjoy a romantic moment, watching fireworks.</desc>
		<image>./images/Monkey-Island-The-Secret-of-Monkey-Island-1990-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19900131T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasfilm Games</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasfilm Games</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Police-Quest-II-The-Vengeance.svm</path>
		<name>Police Quest II: The Vengeance</name>
		<desc>The second game released in the Police Quest franchise. It follows the adventures of Sonny Bonds after his recent promotion to the Homicide squad in the fictional town of Lytton, California in 1988.</desc>
		<image>./images/Police-Quest-II-The-Vengeance-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Police-Quest-III-The-Kindred.svm</path>
		<name>Police Quest III: The Kindred</name>
		<desc>The third game in Sierra's Police Quest series. Based again in Lytton, Sonny Bonds has been promoted, and is forced to deal with both the questionable ethics of a colleague and the attempted murder of his wife, as the sleepy California city is under attack by a deranged serial killer.</desc>
		<image>./images/Police-Quest-III-The-Kindred-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Police-Quest-In-Pursuit-of-the-Death-Angel-1992.svm</path>
		<name>Police Quest: In Pursuit of the Death Angel (1992)</name>
		<desc>This enhanced remake of Police Quest has been completely re-drawn using 256-color VGA graphics. Instead of the text-based interface of the original version, the remake features icons corresponding to the commands Walk, Look, Touch, and Talk for interaction with the game world.

The two versions also have some gameplay-related differences. The driving sequences from the original game have been simplified: the player is no longer required to physically navigate the car and input is limited to making the right turns while the car is driven automatically, and occasionally braking at stop signs. The mandatory poker mini-game during the final segment of the game has been made optional. A few puzzles have different solutions, though not all of those are simplified, and in some instances the puzzles have become more complex in the remake.

Story-wise, the game remains the same for the most part, but it also includes re-written and additional dialogue not seen in the earlier version.</desc>
		<image>./images/Police-Quest-In-Pursuit-of-the-Death-Angel-1992-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sam-and-Max-Hit-the-Road.svm</path>
		<name>Sam &amp; Max Hit the Road</name>
		<desc>Grab your nightstick, squeal like a siren and Hit the Road with Sam &amp; Max, Freelance Police, as they attempt to crack their toughest case. Sam (a shamus canine) and Max (a hyperkinetic rabbity thing) are hot on the trail of a runaway carnival bigfoot across America's quirky underbelly in this deranged animated adventure!

Help our frightening, furry flatfoots find the fugitive freak! Do it now!</desc>
		<image>./images/Sam-and-Max-Hit-the-Road-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19931101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>LucasArts</developer>
		<publisher>LucasArts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Simon-the-Sorcerer-1995.svm</path>
		<name>Simon the Sorcerer (1995)</name>
		<desc>The game was re-released on PC CD-ROM. This new CD came without copy protection, in a jewel case, with a black &amp; white inlay manual, along with colour inserts for both the front and rear. It was advertised with a new Full "Talkie" Soundtrack, which entirely replaced the original subtitles, frustrating some players, including those with hearing disabilities.

The story begins with an ordinary teenager, called Simon, who hears his dog, "Chippy", up in in the loft of his house Seeking to investigate, Simon finds that the dog had discovered a spellbook titled "Ye Olde Spellbooke" in an old chest; both the dog and the book had turned up sometime before the story from an unknown location. Simon throws the book onto the floor in contempt, not believing in magic, only for a portal to open above it as a result. Chippy quickly goes through the portal and Simon follows, ending up in another world. After escaping from some goblins who intended to eat Simon, he quickly discovers a house in a village belonging to a wizard called Calypso, along with a letter from him. Through it, Simon learns he was brought to this world to save Calypso from the evil sorcerer, Sordid.

Instructed to become a wizard, Simon is told to seek out wizards in the local tavern, and complete tasks with them. Helping them to acquire a staff, and paying a subscription fee, he then performs tasks for various people, recovering the spell book he lost, as well as locating Sordid's tower. Gaining entry with a potion that shrinks him, he quickly winds up in the tower's garden and finds a mushroom that restores his size. Searching the tower, Simon helps to send some demons back, and uses a teleporter to take him to the Fiery Pits of Rondor, so as to destroy Sordid's wand. Although Simon transforms him into stone, Sordid is revived the moment his wand is destroyed. Surviving an attempt on his life, Simon quickly outwits him, defeats him, and is sent back to his world.

Although he assumes he had a dream, a portal opens in his bedroom, and a large gloved hand appears, taking him back through it.</desc>
		<image>./images/Simon-the-Sorcerer-1995-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>AdventureSoft</developer>
		<publisher>AdventureSoft</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Simon-the-Sorcerer-II-The-Lion-the-Wizard-and-the-Wardrobe.svm</path>
		<name>Simon the Sorcerer II: The Lion, the Wizard and the Wardrobe</name>
		<desc>The Evil wizard Sordid is brought back to life when a magic-book of his is set ablaze and thrown into the middle of a chalkboard pentagram by the father of Runt, a young boy wanting to become a mighty sorcerer. Sordid promises him that he can become his apprentice if he helps him exact his vengeance on Simon.

Several months later, Sordid's Fortress of Doom is reconstructed and Sordid has a new robotic body. He sends a magical wardrobe to fetch Simon but it accidentally ends up on the doorstep of Calypso, the wizard Simon had to save in the last game. Simon then starts to look for a fuel called mucusade which he needs to power the wardrobe in order to get home.</desc>
		<image>./images/Simon-the-Sorcerer-II-The-Lion-the-Wizard-and-the-Wardrobe-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>AdventureSoft</developer>
		<publisher>AdventureSoft</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space-Quest-II-Vohauls-Revenge-1987.svm</path>
		<name>Space Quest II: Vohaul's Revenge (1987)</name>
		<desc>The ace janitor Roger Wilco thought he'd seen the last of Sludge Vohaul. However, like every evil scientist is supposed to, Vohaul returns with an even meaner scheme. This time he intends to infest the planet Xenon with thousands of genetically engineered door-to-door life insurance salesmen. The last thing he wants is Roger messing things up, and so the brave janitor is captured and brought to the planet Labion to spend the rest of his days working in Vohaul's mines. Fortunately, the shuttle that takes him to the mines crashes, and Roger is the only survivor. He will have to survive the dangers of the jungle planet Labion, and eventually stop Vohaul from executing his mad plan.</desc>
		<image>./images/Space-Quest-II-Vohauls-Revenge-1987-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space-Quest-III-The-Pirates-of-Pestulon.svm</path>
		<name>Space Quest III: The Pirates of Pestulon</name>
		<desc>Narrowly escaping the events of Space Quest II: Vohaul's Revenge, Roger Wilco's escape pod floats through space. As just another metallic item of junk, it's soon picked up by an interstellar garbage hauler. Waking up in a pile of trash, quite familiar for this janitor-turned-hero, Roger Wilco must somehow escape. Once given access to the rest of the galaxy, he'll soon find himself having to avoid a collections cyborg for payments overdue, dealing with the corporate prison of software company Scummsoft, and having to digest the greasy food from the galaxy's finest hamburger joint.</desc>
		<image>./images/Space-Quest-III-The-Pirates-of-Pestulon-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890322T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space-Quest-IV-The-Time-Rippers-1992.svm</path>
		<name>Space Quest IV: The Time Rippers (1992)</name>
		<desc>The game was released on CD-ROM in December 1992 with full speech support and featuring Laugh-In announcer Gary Owens as the voice of the narrator. It featured 256-color hand painted graphics and a fully mouse-driven interface. It was one of the first games to use motion capture animation.

Following his humorous adventures in previous game, Roger Wilco is relaxing at his favorite pub somewhere in time and space when heavily armed soldiers enter the room. Carrying a parting message from Roger's old nemesis, Sludge Vohaul, they plan to get rid of the janitorial hero, execution style. That is, until a man with an over-sized hair dryer helps Roger escape through a time rip into the future. Now Roger Wilco has woken up on his home planet, some time in a meta-fictional Space Quest XII. It is a grim, dystopian future: the series has gone to ruin without its hero, and Vohaul rules supreme. Roger must find a way to avoid Vohaul's henchmen, fulfill his destiny, and learn about a few surprises that await him in his own future.</desc>
		<image>./images/Space-Quest-IV-The-Time-Rippers-1992-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0</rating>
		<releasedate>19921201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space-Quest-V-The-Next-Mutation.svm</path>
		<name>Space Quest V: The Next Mutation</name>
		<desc>After travelling back and forth through time in the previous game, Roger Wilco is back in the Starfleet Acadamy, serving as both a cadet and a janitor. Cheating his way through the Starfleet Aptitude Test, Roger is finally given the rank of captain, his own ship (a garbage scow) and a mission: to explore strange new worlds (which no man in his right mind would explore), to seek out new life and new civilizations (which grew out of the massive amounts of trash Roger will collect on his way), to boldly go where no man has gone before. Step by step Roger will have to unveil a galaxy-wide biohazardous material dumping scheme, solve the mystery of the disappearance of a fellow Starfleet captain and his ship, and confront an agent of an old nemesis.</desc>
		<image>./images/Space-Quest-V-The-Next-Mutation-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930205T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra On-Line, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Space-Quest-The-Sarien-Encounter-1991.svm</path>
		<name>Space Quest: The Sarien Encounter (1991)</name>
		<desc>Space Quest 1: Roger Wilco in the Sarien Encounter is a remake of the original release of Space Quest: Chapter I - The Sarien Encounter. The new version has enhanced graphics (256 color VGA) and soundblaster support. It uses the SCI game engine (point-and-click interface, icons along the top) rather than the AGI engine (mixed point-and-click with text parser). Some of the puzzles have been slightly changed to accommodate the new interface and it is also possible to skip the arcade part. There are a few additional scenes and more elaborate text descriptions, mostly enhancing the humorous effect.</desc>
		<image>./images/Space-Quest-The-Sarien-Encounter-1991-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The-7th-Guest.svm</path>
		<name>The 7th Guest</name>
		<desc>Henry Stauf's mansion had been abandoned for as long as anyone dare remember. Stauf was a master toy maker, a maker of amazing puzzles and this strange house was his greatest creation. Now, the mansion stands empty, rotting ever since the children started dying, ever since the six guests came. Now there are only the eerie lights and the terrible sing-song rhymes of the children...
And suddenly, you are in the house. You move from room to haunted room, step by terrifying step, as scenes from that night of horror come to life. Because Stauf's game isn't over. There were six guests the world knew about - and there was one other. Stauf's mad mansion lives again. And only you can end the nightmare and learn the secret of The 7th Guest.</desc>
		<image>./images/The-7th-Guest-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Trilobyte</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The-Dig.svm</path>
		<name>The Dig</name>
		<desc>A DEEP SPACE ADVENTURE BY SEAN CLARK IN COLLABORATION WITH FILMMAKER STEVEN SPIELBERG.</desc>
		<image>./images/The-Dig-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950111T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>LucasArts</developer>
		<publisher>LucasArts</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Toonstruck.svm</path>
		<name>Toonstruck</name>
		<desc>Drew Blanc is a cartoon animator and the original creator of the Fluffy Fluffy Bun Bun Show. This show has been an unprecedented ten year success for his company, but in reality the many cute talking rabbits that star in the show sicken him. His self-revered creation, Flux Wildly, a wise-talking and sarcastic small purple character, has been denied the chance of starring in his own show. Drew's boss, Sam Schmaltz (played by Ben Stein), sets him the task of designing more bunnies to co-star in the Fluffy Fluffy Bun Bun Show by the next morning. However, the depressed animator soon nods off, suffering from acute artist's block. He wakes early the next morning to inexplicably find his television switched on, announcing the Fluffy Fluffy Bun Bun Show. Suddenly, Drew is mysteriously drawn into the television screen and transported to an idyllic two-dimensional cartoon world populated by his own creations, among many other cartoon characters. He soon befriends Flux Wildly (Dan Castellaneta), and discovers that this fictional paradise is being ravaged by a ruthless new character with a devastating weapon of evil, a flying machine equipped with a ray beam that mutates the pleasant, childish landscape and its inhabitants into dark, twisted and mean counterpart versions of themselves. He is tasked with hunting down and stopping this madman, thereby restoring peace and harmony to the land, in return for safe passage back to three-dimensional reality.</desc>
		<image>./images/Toonstruck-image.jpg</image>
		<developer>Burst</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Touche-The-Adventures-of-the-Fifth-Musketeer.svm</path>
		<name>Touché: The Adventures of the Fifth Musketeer</name>
		<desc>Geoffroi Le Brun, ensign in His Majesty’s musketeers, arrives in the middle of the night in 16th century Rouen, France, to start his new posting at the musketeer headquarters. At the moment he arrives, the unfortunate Comte d’Itee, William de Peuple, is attacked by bandits and his precious will is stolen. Geoffroi offers him, just before he dies, his assistance to find his will.

Of course, getting it back will not be easy, and he must travel back and forth across France to accomplish his quest, visiting the cities of Amiens, St Quentin, Le Mans, Paris, and Le Havre. However, he is assisted by a clever manservant, called Henri, who will be a great help, without any doubt. With some luck, he will hunt the murderer(s) down and find the will. And who knows, maybe he will meet a beautiful lady or find a fortune on the way.

Touché: The Adventures of the Fifth Musketeer is a humorous, inventory-based point and click adventure game. By right-clicking on a hotspot a context-sensitive action interface pops up, showing the relevant actions. The game is a full talkie with captions, music and sound effects. It features a progressive traveling map, which allows to visit new locations after having solved various puzzles.</desc>
		<image>./images/Touche-The-Adventures-of-the-Fifth-Musketeer-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Clipper Software</developer>
		<publisher>U.S. Gold</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Zak-McKracken-and-the-Alien-Mindbenders.svm</path>
		<name>Zak McKracken and the Alien Mindbenders</name>
		<desc>The plot follows Zak (full name Francis Zachary McKracken), a writer for the National Inquisitor, a tabloid newspaper; Annie Larris, a freelance scientist; and Melissa China and Leslie Bennett, two Yale University coed students, in their attempt to prevent the nefarious alien Caponians (who have infiltrated the phone company) from slowly reducing the intelligence of everybody on Earth using a 60 Hz "hum".</desc>
		<image>./images/Zak-McKracken-and-the-Alien-Mindbenders-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Lucasfilm Games</developer>
		<publisher>Lucasfilm Games</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
</gameList>
