<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Halloween Harry - Alien Carnage (1993) (3drealms.com).conf</path>
		<name>Alien Carnage</name>
		<desc>Alien Carnage (also known as Halloween Harry) is a follow-up to the 1985 game Halloween Harry, created for the Microbee System by John Passfield in 1985, but it has very little in common with the original game.

In this side-scrolling platformer, earth is being invaded by aliens who turn humans into zombies in order to enslave them. Harry is the only saviour of earth, and he has to traverse different levels and rescue the kidnapped humans. There are many different weapons to collect, and most have a limited amount of ammo.</desc>
		<image>./images/Halloween Harry - Alien Carnage (1993) (3drealms.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19931010T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Interactive Binary Illusions</developer>
		<publisher>Apogee Software, Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Alone in the Dark 1992 (1992) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Alone in the Dark (1992)</name>
		<desc>In 1924, Jeremy Hartwood, a noted artist and the owner of the Louisiana mansion Derceto, has committed suicide by hanging himself. His death appears suspicious yet seems to surprise no-one, for Derceto is widely reputed to be haunted by an evil power. The case is quickly dealt with by the police and soon forgotten by the public. The player assumes the role of either Edward Carnby - a private investigator who is sent to find a piano in the loft for an antique dealer - or Emily Hartwood, Jeremy's niece, who is also interested in finding the piano because she believes a secret drawer in it has a note in which Jeremy explains his suicide. The player, either as Carnby or Hartwood, goes to the mansion to investigate. As the player enters the house, the doors mysteriously slam shut behind him or her. Reluctantly, he or she continues up to the attic. In that room, the action begins.</desc>
		<image>./images/Alone in the Dark 1992 (1992) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Infogrames</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Alone in the Dark II (1993) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Alone In The Dark 2</name>
		<desc>In Alone in the Dark 2, you take the role of detective Edward Carnby, one of the two main characters in the original Alone in the Dark. Carnby is now called upon to investigate a bootlegger named One Eyed Jack after an old detective college name Stryker attributes Jack to the kidnapping of young Grace Saunders. Stryker attempts to infiltrate Jack's dilapidated mansion of Hell's Kitchen and rescue the girl, only to disappear himself. That's where Carnby comes in.

Carnby soon learns that Jack and his gangsters are really 15th century pirates who gained immortality after Jack joined forces with Elizabeth Jarret, a Voodoo witch. However the dark magic which keeps them immortal also requires Jack and his crew to regularly make human sacrifices (which explains Grace's kidnapping).

Now Carnby must battle his way through Hell's Kitchen and Jack's army of tommy-gun wielding gangsters, searching for a way to break the spell and make them stay dead.</desc>
		<image>./images/Alone in the Dark II (1993) (gog.com)-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19931002T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Infogrames</developer>
		<publisher>Infogrames</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Alone in the Dark III (1995) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Alone in the Dark 3</name>
		<desc>It's 1926 and after Edward Carnby's success in his previous two investigations, a journalist has nicknamed him the 'Supernatural Private Eye'. This time, he is called to investigate the disappearance of a film crew at a two-bit ghost town known by the name of Slaughter Gulch located in the Mojave Desert in California. Among the disappeared crew is Emily Hartwood, Jeremy Hartwood's niece from the original. Edward soon discovers that a curse has gripped the town, and an evil cowboy from the Badlands named Jed Stone is the villain who is responsible for the crew's disappearance. Lurking around town are many trigger-happy sharpshooters, deranged prospectors, and bloodthirsty lost souls whom Edward must ward off with both his strength and his wit.</desc>
		<image>./images/Alone in the Dark III (1995) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950416T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Infogrames</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Bomberman - Dyna Blaster (1990) (bestoldgames.net).conf</path>
		<name>Bomberman</name>
		<desc>The black spaceman kidnapped Bomberman's beloved and brought her to his chambers in the castle, far beyond his reach, over the rivers, forest and mountains. Bomberman's job is to save her, battling the sea of the enemies, with only bombs at his disposal.

The range of Bomberman's bomb explosions can be upgraded with time, but if he dies, the range resets back to the minimum range and Bomberman loses his previous skills. Some updates can make Bomberman walk through the walls, increase his speed, and give him some other assets to aid him in his quest to save the woman he loves.

This top-down action-arcade game consists of nine levels per stage, each tougher than the other, and each final one consisting of the boss that will have to be dealt with. Bomberman can move horizontally and vertically and lay down bombs behind him, thus evaporating the enemies, but beware: Bomberman can block himself with his own bomb, and thus become a victim of his own bomb.</desc>
		<image>./images/Bomberman - Dyna Blaster (1990) (bestoldgames.net)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19900907T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Hudson Soft Company, Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson Soft Company, Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Carmageddon (1997) (Carmageddon Max Pack) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Carmageddon</name>
		<desc>Carmageddon is a violent car racing game where the racing element can be equally important as wrecking opponents' cars or gathering kills by ramming into pedestrians. At the beginning the player has only one car and is ranked at #99. The overall objective is to race all the way to the top, collecting the opponents' cars on the way as trophies (and possibly replacements to one's vehicle). In the race itself the player tries to damage opponents by driving into them, and can also kill pedestrians.

Damage, kills and spectacular moves earn credits for upgrades and even making repairs to the car at anytime during the race. If a specific opponent's car is wrecked multiple times in successive races, it is added to the choice of available vehicles. There are many power-ups strewn around the courses that range from useful (more speed, instant brake) to fun and downright absurd. Though the player can win by racing by finishing first, wrecking everything in sight is encouraged. The game offers open environments where exploration away from the racing course is encouraged.</desc>
		<image>./images/Carmageddon (1997) (Carmageddon Max Pack) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19970630T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Stainless Games</developer>
		<publisher>SCi Games</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Carmageddon - Splat Pack (1997) (Carmageddon Max Pack) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Carmageddon: Splat Pack</name>
		<desc>The Carmageddon Splat Pack was the only official expansion pack for Carmageddon. Released in November 1997, it added several new cars, power-ups and levels.</desc>
		<image>./images/Carmageddon - Splat Pack (1997) (Carmageddon Max Pack) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19970101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Stainless Software Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay Productions, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Command &amp; Conquer - Tiberian Dawn (1995) (Virgin).conf</path>
		<name>Command &amp; Conquer</name>
		<desc>Command &amp; Conquer was released in 1995 as the first installment of the identically named RTS series developed by Westwood Studios. Set in an alternate history 1995, Command &amp; Conquer tells the story of two globalized factions: the Global Defense Initiative of the United Nations, and the ancient quasi-cult, quasi-state organization, the Brotherhood of Nod. These two factions become locked in a mortal struggle for control over a mysterious resource known as Tiberium that is slowly spreading and infecting the world.</desc>
		<image>./images/Command &amp; Conquer - Tiberian Dawn (1995) (Virgin)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19950831T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Westwood Studios</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Command &amp; Conquer - Red Alert (1996) (commandandconquer.com).conf</path>
		<name>Command &amp; Conquer - Red Alert</name>
		<desc>Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert is the 2nd release in Westwoods Real-Time-Strategy series Command &amp; Conquer and was published in 1996 by Virgin Interactive. Red Alert takes place during an unspecified period in the 1950s of a parallel universe, which was inadvertently created by Albert Einstein in a failed attempt to prevent the horrors of World War II.
Starting off in 1946, at the Trinity site in New Mexico, the opening to Red Alert shows Albert Einstein as he is preparing to travel backwards through space and time. After his experimental "Chronosphere" device is activated, he finds himself in Landsberg, Germany, in the year 1924, where he meets a young Adolf Hitler just after the latter's release from Landsberg Prison. Following a brief conversation between the two, Einstein shakes Hitler's hand, and this somehow eliminates Hitler's existence from time and returns Einstein to his point of origin.
With the threat of Nazi Germany having been successfully removed from history, the Soviet Union began to grow increasingly powerful under the rule of Joseph Stalin. Had Adolf Hitler risen to power, Nazi Germany would have emerged as a force standing in the way of Stalin's own ambitions of conquest. Instead, left unweakened, the USSR proceeds by seizing lands from China and then begins invading Eastern Europe, in order to achieve Joseph Stalin's vision of a Soviet Union stretching across the entire Eurasian landmass. In response, the nations of Europe form into the Alliance, and start a grim and desperate guerrilla war against the invading Soviet army. Over the course of the game's story, the Allies and Soviets fight out a devastating conflict for control over the European mainland, in what has become an alternate World War II.</desc>
		<image>./images/Command &amp; Conquer - Red Alert (1996) (commandandconquer.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19961031T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Westwood Studios</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./DOSBox command prompt.conf</path>
		<name>DOSBox</name>
		<image>./images/DOSBox command prompt-image.png</image>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<genre></genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Duke Nukem (1991) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Duke Nukem</name>
		<desc>Set in the year 1997, your mission is to stop Dr. Proton, a madman bent on ruling the world with his army of Techbots. As the irrepressible hero Duke Nukem, you'll chase Dr. Proton deep into the Earth, then to his lunar space station, and eventually into the Earth's nuclear ravished future.</desc>
		<image>./images/Duke Nukem (1991) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19910701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Apogee Software</developer>
		<publisher>Apogee Software</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Duke Nukem II (1993) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Duke Nukem II</name>
		<desc>In the "near future" year 1998, the evil Rigelatins plan to enslave Earth, and they kidnap Duke Nukem (who was performing in an interview about his new autobiography, "Why I'm So Great"), to use his brain to plot the attack for their forces. Duke must break free in order to save the world, once again.</desc>
		<image>./images/Duke Nukem II (1993) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19931203T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Apogee Software Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Apogee Software Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dune (1992) (CD).conf</path>
		<name>Dune</name>
		<desc>Based on the legendary Frank Herbert novel of the same name and visually inspired by the 1984 David Lynch movie, Dune is a strategy-adventure hybrid where the player takes the role of young Paul Atreides, the son of Duke Leto. The Emperor Shaddam Corrino IV has given the Atreides House the rights to manage the extraction of the most precious substance in the entire universe - the Melange, commonly known as Spice in the desolate desert planet Arrakis (Dune), the only place in the universe capable of producing the substance. While everything indicates the offer is a trap orchestrated by their enemies the Harkonnen, the Atreides family agrees on moving, as he who controls the spice, controls the universe.</desc>
		<image>./images/Dune (1992) (CD)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Cryo Interactive Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Games, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Dune II - The Building of a Dynasty (1992) (+ Super Dune II Classic (2009)).conf</path>
		<name>Dune II: The Building of a Dynasty</name>
		<desc>The planet Arrakis (also known as Dune for its sandy landscape) is the only place in the known universe where Melange (more commonly known as the Spice) can be found. The Spice is the basis of interstellar travel and thus the standard of the Imperial economy. To increase productivity, The Padishah Emperor has invited three powerful Houses (Harkonnen, Atreides and Ordos) to compete against one another economically and bring up spice production. Competition among these houses begins peacefully but soon turns ugly as they battle each other with armed troops, advanced weaponry, and spies. The planet itself is also hostile, with dangerous sandworms inhabiting the spice fields.

Dune II is often considered the first mainstream modern real-time strategy game and established many conventions of the genre. Even though set in Frank Herbert's famous Dune universe, the game is only loosely connected to the plot of any of the books or the films based from them. Controlling either of the three Houses, the player must fight a number of battles against the other Houses. In the early levels, the goal is simply to earn a certain number of credits, while in the later missions, all enemies must be destroyed.

The single resource in the game is the Spice, which must be collected by harvesters. The spice is converted to credits in a refinery, which are then spent to construct additional buildings and units. There are two terrain types: buildings can only be constructed on stone, while the Spice is only found on sand. However, units moving on sand attract the large sandworms of Dune, who are virtually indestructible and can swallow even large units whole. As levels progress, new and more advanced buildings and units are made available, including structures like a radar station, a repair facility or defense turrets and, for units, various ground troops, light vehicles and tanks. Each House can construct one unique special unit, and, after building a palace improvement, can unleash a unique palace effect.

After a mission is completed, the player can select the next mission on a map of Dune. This choice determines the layout of the next map to be played, but has no effect on the overall campaign.</desc>
		<image>./images/Dune II - The Building of a Dynasty (1992) (+ Super Dune II Classic (2009))-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19921201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Westwood Studios, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Games, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Grand Theft Auto (1997).conf</path>
		<name>Grand Theft Auto</name>
		<desc>Drive dozens of varied vehicles around three of America's toughest cities. Only the best will be able to tame the fastest cars. Only the smartest will know all the short-cuts and the whereabouts of the hottest wheels. Only the toughest will be able to take on the world and finish the job like a professional...</desc>
		<image>./images/Grand Theft Auto (1997)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19971001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>DMA Design</developer>
		<publisher>BMG Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Grand Theft Auto - London 1961 (1999).conf</path>
		<name>Grand Theft Auto: London 1961</name>
		<desc>Grand Theft Auto: Mission Pack #2 - London 1961 is a freely distributed mission pack to Grand Theft Auto and Grand Theft Auto: London 1969. This time, you explore 1961 London in one of 22 new vehicles as well as engage combat in a new deathmatch map (roughly based on real-life Manchester.) Released only in downloadable form, available for free. London 1961 requires London 1969, which, in turn, requires Grand Theft Auto. It can also only be played with the original London 1969 disc; it does not work with the version included in the Grand Theft Auto: The Classics Collection pack.</desc>
		<image>./images/Grand Theft Auto - London 1961 (1999)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19990601T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>DMA Design</developer>
		<publisher>Take-Two Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Grand Theft Auto - London 1969 (1999).conf</path>
		<name>Grand Theft Auto: London 1969</name>
		<desc>Grand Theft Auto: Mission Pack #1 - London 1969 is an official expansion pack to Grand Theft Auto. Instead of the fictional interpretations of New York, Miami and Los Angeles of the original, this game opens up the city of London to the player. The game features thirty new vehicles, new graphics and thirty-two new missions; all in a distinctly British theme. The new city contains many familiar landmarks from London in the late 60s as well as other cultural reference and Cockney slang. This time the player can choose the avatar's appearance, otherwise gameplay has not been changed from the original game. The player still is involved in organized crime and must perform a variety of criminal activities.</desc>
		<image>./images/Grand Theft Auto - London 1969 (1999)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19990331T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>DMA Design</developer>
		<publisher>Take-Two Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Heroes of Might and Magic - A Strategic Quest (1995) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Heroes of Might and Magic</name>
		<desc>Heroes of Might and Magic tells the story of Lord Morglin Ironfist, who is forced to flee his homeland through a magical portal, because his cousin, Ragnar, had usurped the throne after his uncle, Ragnar's father, killed Ironfist's father, the legitimate owner of the throne.
He finds himself along with his few followers in a strange and uncharted land, called Enroth. The land is unruled but contested by Ironfist and three other warlords: the barbarian Lord Slayer, the sorceress Queen Lamanda, and the warlock Lord Alamar.</desc>
		<image>./images/Heroes of Might and Magic - A Strategic Quest (1995) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950831T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>New World Computing, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>New World Computing, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Heroes of Might and Magic II - The Succession Wars (1996) (+ The Price of Loyalty (1997)) (HoMM2 Gold) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Heroes of Might and Magic II</name>
		<desc>The canonical ending of Heroes I results in Lord Morglin Ironfist's victory. In the following years, he has successfully unified the continent of Enroth and secured his rule as king. Upon the king's death, his two sons, Archibald and Roland, vie for the crown. Archibald orchestrates a series of events that lead to Roland's exile. Archibald is then declared the new king, while Roland organizes a resistance. Each alignment is represented by one of the game's two campaigns. Archibald's campaign features the three "evil" town alignments, while Roland's campaign features the three "good" town alignments.
If Archibald is victorious, Roland's rebellion is crushed, and Roland himself is imprisoned in Castle Ironfist, leaving Archibald the uncontested ruler of Enroth. The canonical ending, however, results in Roland's victory, with Archibald being turned to stone by Roland's court wizard, Tanir.</desc>
		<image>./images/Heroes of Might and Magic II - The Succession Wars (1996) (+ The Price of Loyalty (1997)) (HoMM2 Gold) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19961001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>New World Computing</developer>
		<publisher>3do</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jack in the Dark (1993) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Jack in the Dark</name>
		<desc>Jack in the Dark is a spin-off game made during Alone in the Dark 2's development. It was used as a promotional game, distributed at Christmas 1993. The game was on a single floppy disk in a golden wrap featuring a Jack-in-the-box illustration on top. Later CD versions of both Alone in the Dark and Alone in the Dark 2 came packaged with Jack in the Dark.

It is Halloween, and Grace Saunders is out for tricks or treats, when she enters a small toy store and gets locked in. The Jack-in-the-Box laughs, the toys play and walk by themselves and hold a dark secret. Grace must discover what secret is that and figure out a way to leave this somewhat eccentric toy store, governed by a somewhat psychopathic Jack-in-the-Box.</desc>
		<image>./images/Jack in the Dark (1993) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19931215T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Interplay</developer>
		<publisher>Atari</publisher>
		<genre></genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jazz Jackrabbit (1994) (+ Holiday Hare 1994 (1994)) (CD-ROM).conf</path>
		<name>Jazz Jackrabbit</name>
		<desc>Jazz Jackrabbit is a platform game developed and published by Epic MegaGames. It was released in 1994 for PCs operating DOS, with subsequent Macintosh and Microsoft Windows releases in 1995 and 1996. It was one of the first games to bring the side-scrolling platformer style - common on gaming consoles - to a PC audience.

Jazz Jackrabbit was greatly inspired by the Amiga game Zool and the ongoing success of video game classics (such as Sonic the Hedgehog and Mega Man) defining the platform game genre in the 1990s market, and was initially considered to be a pastiche of Sega's Sonic the Hedgehog in the computer world. The game did not manage to reach the popularity of Sonic, but did acquire a certain fan audience due to its fast-paced gameplay, advanced graphics and notorious acid jazz level soundtracks.

In 1995, PC Format magazine named Jazz Jackrabbit "Arcade Game of the Year". Two other releases originated from it: a sequel named Jazz Jackrabbit 2 in 1998, as well as a reboot on Game Boy Advance in 2002. The commercial success of the game kickstarted the career of its co-creator, Cliffy Bleszinski, who would later go on to be a key force behind Epic Games' blockbuster hits Unreal Tournament and Gears of War, among other titles.</desc>
		<image>./images/Jazz Jackrabbit (1994) (+ Holiday Hare 1994 (1994)) (CD-ROM)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19940730T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Epic Megagames</developer>
		<publisher>Epic Megagames</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Jazz Jackrabbit - Holiday Hare 1995 (1995).conf</path>
		<name>Jazz Jackrabbit: Holiday Hare 1995</name>
		<desc>Jazz Jackrabbit: Holiday Hare 1995 is a standalone add-on for Jazz Jackrabbit. It was sometimes distributted as a demo with other games.</desc>
		<image>./images/Jazz Jackrabbit - Holiday Hare 1995 (1995)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<developer>Epic Megagames</developer>
		<publisher>Epic Megagames</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Little Big Adventure (1994) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Little Big Adventure</name>
		<desc>ELCOME TO LITTLE BIG ADVENTURE!

In designing and making this game, we have tried to maintain a certain
philosophy of gameplay based on the following points:

An easy to use interface that lets the player concentrate on the game, not
the controls, but which also allows for a deep and rich gameplay experience.

Maximum interaction with the game enviroment. This includes interaction with
the background, as well as the different characters. The player is not stuck
on a single path through the game, and the choices you make truly affect the
enviroment and the outcome of the game.

In tone, we have striven to produce a realistic, yet slightly cartoonish
enviroment. We hope this enhances the player's enjoyment of the game, and
intensifies the story's interesting mix of humour and drama.

Little Big Adventure is a strange and mysterious journey through a surreal
and dangerous world. You take the role of Twinsen, a young Quetch entreated
in a dream by the Goddess Sendell to come to your planet's rescue. It is your
destiny to restore peace and harmony to your world. You begin your quest
imprisoned in an asylum. From the start it is difficult to know whom to trust
or where to go. The tyrant Dr. Funfrock has taken over your home planet of
Twinsun and has imposed his brutal methods of control over the entire
population. His primary weapons are his ability to clone different species
and teleport these clones anywhere on the planet. There are four main species
on the planet: Quetches (Twinsen is a member of this pony-tailed group),
Grobos (they look like elephants), Spheros (round little guys) and
Rabibunnies.

All species suffer under his reign of terror, but few are capable of
resistance. You must find those who can help you, travelling great distances
in your quest to save the world and stop the evil Dr. Funfrock. At any moment
your enemies may overtake you, stopping you in your pursuit of the quest. Be
wary and you will find a glorious tribute awaits your success.</desc>
		<image>./images/Little Big Adventure (1994) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19941001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Adeline Software International</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Little Big Adventure II (1997) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Little Big Adventure 2</name>
		<desc>After Twinsen defeated FunFrock at the end of Little Big Adventure, Twinsun was peaceful, until a sudden storm covered Citadel Island. The Dino-Fly, a creature encountered in LBA 1 is struck by lightning and crashes in Twinsen and Zoe's garden. Twinsen seeks help from Ker'aooc, a healing wizard, who lives on Desert Island. But ferry crossings are cancelled. He aids Bersimon, the island's weather wizard, resulting in the clouds disappearing. After the storm, alien creatures, who call themselves Esmers, land on the planet, under a false diplomatic guise and Twinsen begins training under the Wizard's School after hearing of missing children on the planet. The Esmers use their army to secretly capture Twinsun's Children and openly invite the Wizards to their planet(which is revealed later to be a trap to capture them). After graduating as a Wizard, Twinsen is informed by his master of the possible plot of the Esmers and is sent to investigate their planet by accepting their invitation to all Wizards. Once Twinsen lands in Zeelich (the Esmers' two-layered, Jupiter-like gas home planet), the invitation proves to be a trap and he is arrested on the landing port. After tricking one of the guards with the help of another prisoner, Twinsen manages to escape imprisonment and escapes the planet in one of the ships. He eventually crashes in the mountains of Citadel Island, where he is attacked by an Esmerian soldier, after defeating him and making his way into the city he finds out that the Esmers have taken over the planet and have imposed martial law. After going home to check on Zoe he finds out that Baldino has left him a protopack (Prototype Jetpack; it can hover, not fly) in the warehouse, he retrieves it and sets out to find his friend. Once making it to Desert Island he finds out that Baldino has disappeared, he proceeds to investigate his house discovers that Baldino has built a spacecraft and for some reason went to Emerald Moon (Twinsun's moon), he also visits the Wizard's School and learns from his master that in order to proceed in his journey and face the Esmers, who prove to be more than he can handle.

Home to several different species, Zeelich is a two-layered planet, the upper layer located above the sea of toxic gas that plagues the planet. The lower layer is located beneath the gas. Its inhabitants await the day when a certain prophecy will be fulfilled, and the Dark Monk, the shadow god, will emerge and restore Zeelich.

Twinsen eventually gathers together four fragments making up a key which must be placed inside a little temple on Celebration Island. He unmasks Dark Monk, who is really FunFrock, the villain from the first game. He kills FunFrock, and returns to stop the moon of Twinsun crashing into the planet.</desc>
		<image>./images/Little Big Adventure II (1997) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>1</rating>
		<releasedate>19970531T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Adeline Software International</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./MDK - Murder Death Kill (1997) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>MDK</name>
		<desc>In this 3D shoot 'em up, you play Kurt, and your job is to save the world. Aliens have sent 8 giant fortresses to destroy earth. You run and jump through 6 missions of strange 3D worlds and kill the "Stream Riders" with your machine gun arm. Precise platform jumps are part of the challenge.

Kurt is equipped with a special battle suit with an included parachute and a sniper interface (allowing you to aim precise shooting while standing still) embedded in your helmet. Further weaponry enhancements are available as you progress through the game.</desc>
		<image>./images/MDK - Murder Death Kill (1997) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>1</rating>
		<releasedate>19970701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Shiny</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Microsoft Windows 3.11 (1993).conf</path>
		<name>Microsoft Windows 3.11</name>
		<image>./images/Microsoft Windows 3.11 (1993)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Microsoft</developer>
		<publisher>Microsoft</publisher>
		<genre></genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mortal Kombat (1993) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Mortal Kombat</name>
		<desc>Five Hundred years ago, an ancient and well respected Shaolin fighting tournament, held every 50 years, was corrupted by an evil and elderly sorcerer by the name of Shang Tsung. Shang was accompanied by Prince Goro, a warrior of the Shokan race (a four armed half-human/half-dragon). Knowing that if ten tournaments in a row were won by the Outworld champion, the Earth Realm would be conquered by evil and fall into darkness, Shang entered Goro in the tournament and had him defeat the great Kung Lao. Goro has been reigning supreme as the undefeated fighting champion for five hundred years now. As the last tournament required draws near, Raiden, Thunder God and protector of the Earth Realm, enacts a plan to tip the scales in the humans favor, Seven fighters step into the arena on Shang Tsung's mysterious island: Shaolin warrior Liu Kang, Special Forces operative Sonya Blade, the mercenary thug Kano, fame-seeking actor Johnny Cage, the ice wielding Lin Kuei warrior Sub-Zero and his undead adversary Scorpion, and Raiden himself.

Mortal Kombat is a side-scrolling 1 on 1 fighting game. Fighting is set as one on one kombat, allowing each player to perform a variety of punches, kicks, and special moves in order to defeat their opponent. When the opponent faces their second round loss, the winner can perform a finishing move called a "Fatality" on the loser. The Fatality is a move unique to each fighter that graphically kills the loser in a blood-soaked finale.

Mortal Kombat began its life as a 2-player arcade title. It is notable for its use of digitized actors to represent the game's fighters, as well as its use of copious amounts of blood during gameplay.</desc>
		<image>./images/Mortal Kombat (1993) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Midway Games, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Acclaim Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mortal Kombat III (1995) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Mortal Kombat 3</name>
		<desc>Shao Kahn has won. The Earthrealm is no more. In order to revive his Queen Sindel, the emperor Shao Kahn used the Outworld Tournament from Mortal Kombat 2 as a diversion while his Shadow Priests revive his fallen Queen on Earth. Once enacted, the dimensional bridge between the two realms connects, allowing Kahn's extermination squads to invade and destroy Earth, and enslave the population's souls.

A small team of Raiden's "Chosen Warriors" survives the attack: Mortal Kombat champion Liu Kang and his ally Kung Lao, Special Forces agents Sonya Blade and Jax, the shaman Nightwolf, the riot cop Stryker, the nomadic Kabal, and former Lin Kuei warrior Sub-Zero, who has gone rogue from his clan. Facing the warriors are the mercenary Kano, cyber-ninjas Smoke, Sektor and Cyrax, Sheeva, a female Shokan, the sorcerer Shang Tsung, and Queen Sindel herself.

Mortal Kombat 3 brings new elements to the 2D fighting series: multi-level playfields, "Dial-A-Combo" attacks, a "Run" button to speed up the battles, and "Vs." codes, which unlock new powers and abilities once both players enter a code sequence in pre-match-up screens. Also included are more stage fatalities and finishing moves as each warrior attempts to go one-on-one with the Centaurian enforcer Motaro, and Shao Kahn himself.

Mortal Kombat 3 is the last traditional one-on-one fighting game game in the series to feature motion-captured digitized graphics for its kombatants, and introduces online network play to the PC version</desc>
		<image>./images/Mortal Kombat III (1995) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Midway Games, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Atari, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mortal Kombat II (1994) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Mortal Kombat II</name>
		<desc>The Mortal Kombat fighters, plus several new ones, return for a tournament held by the evil Shang Tsung of the Outworld. The action is one-on-one as before, and famed for its high level of violence and blood (other than the sanitised Nintendo version). There are 5 difficulty levels and optional credits, as well as the usual two player mode including same character duels.

To win the main tournament, the player must beat each of the other human players, before taking on Shang Tsung, Kintaro and finally Shao Kahn. Players have a range of punches and kicks available, as well as flying kicks, uppercuts, roundhouses, and the special moves, which vary for each player. These include throws, uppercuts, long-distance bullets, bicycle kicks and a teleport feature.</desc>
		<image>./images/Mortal Kombat II (1994) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Midway Games, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Acclaim Entertainment, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Phantasmagoria (1995) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Phantasmagoria</name>
		<desc>Phantasmagoria is an adventure game that places heavy emphasis on full motion video for exposition and cutscenes at various junctures to advance the storyline. Adrienne is represented as a digitized character roaming around pre-rendered settings in the house. She inspects various rooms, finds items, adds them to her inventory, finds places to use the items, and triggers advancements in the plot. 

Puzzle-solving element is present, though reduced compared to most other adventure games made by Sierra. There are seven chapters in the game, as well as a status screen that tracks the player's progress within the chapter. If the player happens to get stuck in the game, a talking skull icon who identifies himself as the hintkeeper can supply the player with hints on request. It is possible to start playing the game from any chapter.</desc>
		<image>./images/Phantasmagoria (1995) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19950731T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Phantasmagoria II - A Puzzle of Flesh (1996) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Phantasmagoria: A Puzzle of Flesh</name>
		<desc>Phantasmagoria: A Puzzle of Flesh is not an actual sequel to the original Phantasmagoria, but rather a follow-up that has similar themes and visual concept. The game is more heavy on puzzles and traditional adventure gameplay than its predecessor. The gameplay involves standard activities found in adventure games, including extended conversations with the characters featuring selectable dialogue topics, collecting and manipulating inventory items with the environment, etc. It is possible (and often necessary) to call characters on the phone, as well as check and answer e-mails accessed by the player character's computer at his workplace.</desc>
		<image>./images/Phantasmagoria II - A Puzzle of Flesh (1996) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19961130T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sierra</developer>
		<publisher>Sierra</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ports of Call (1989) (portsofcall.de).conf</path>
		<name>Ports of Call</name>
		<desc>Ports of Call gives you the job of a shipowner. First you have to choose your hometown and after that you have to buy your first used ship. Then you have to charter freight and bring it to its destination. With this profit you can buy new ships and so on and on. You also have to repair your ships regularly. If you do not your ships will sink to the oceans.

Ports of Call is a classic German business simulation with some action sequences. In this sequences you must steer your ship into the port or have to rescue some shipwrecked people.</desc>
		<image>./images/Ports of Call (1989) (portsofcall.de)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Aegis Interactive Software</developer>
		<publisher>Aegis Interactive Software</publisher>
		<genre>Construction and Management Simulation</genre>
		<players>4+</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Prehistorik (1991) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Prehistorik</name>
		<desc>Prehistorik is a side-view platform game with a superficial similarity to Chuck Rock. You control a neanderthal who must march through hostile pre-historic environments seeking food and keeping himself safe. Some food can be found in caves, but it mainly exists in living animal forms.

These include fire-breathing Pyro-Tax dragons, the Turtosaurus, and the Bad Bat. Each of these must be clubbed to death, some taking up to 5 hits, and then walked over. Some other enemies are indestructible, with the monkeys who throw coconuts at you particularly fiendish.

You will have to complete the level within the time limit, and avoid contact with these foes. However, bombs and improved weapons can be collected, as can extra lives, time bonuses and an improved jump.</desc>
		<image>./images/Prehistorik (1991) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Titus France SA</developer>
		<publisher>Titus France SA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Prehistorik II (1993) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Prehistorik 2</name>
		<desc>Prehistorik 2 takes up the story of its predecessor, for another caveman-era platform game. 

The hero must use his club to crush animal enemies, many of which then release bonus items to collect. He no longer needs to feed his clan, so there is no required minimum food target, unlike the original game. Other bonus items are located around the levels, while yet more can be found by using your club creatively and adventurously. 

Passwords for every level can be found written in various places and they are different on every computer. You also encounter bosses after every few levels. In addition, the game includes hidden locations, multiple level exits and even hidden levels.</desc>
		<image>./images/Prehistorik II (1993) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Titus France SA</developer>
		<publisher>Titus France SA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Prince of Persia (1989).conf</path>
		<name>Prince of Persia</name>
		<desc>Prince of Persia was originally released in 1989 for the Apple II by Jordan Mechner. Mechner used film of his younger brother David running, jumping, and performing many of the Prince's actions. Mechner then rotoscoped the film to create the animations that give the Prince his fluid movement.

Part of the game's appeal was its then unique focus on environmental puzzle-solving, as well as its one-on-one sword duels. Mechner has stated that the game was inspired by the first ten minutes of Raiders of the Lost Ark, for the character's acrobatics in a dangerous environment.

Prince of Persia has since been ported to a number of different platforms, including the Amiga, Apple Macintosh, DOS, NES, Game Boy, Sega Genesis, Game Gear, SNES, Sharp X68000, Atari ST, and SAM Coupé.

The music was written by Jordan Mechner's father, Francis Mechner.</desc>
		<image>./images/Prince of Persia (1989)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19891003T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Brøderbund Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Brøderbund Software, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Prince of Persia II - The Shadow &amp; The Flame (1993).conf</path>
		<name>Prince of Persia 2: The Shadow &amp; The Flame</name>
		<desc>Your identity has been taken by the evil Grand Vizier Jaffar whom you defeated in the original Prince of Persia. Banished from your palace, you must fight to reclaim what is yours and save the Sultan's lovely daughter.</desc>
		<image>./images/Prince of Persia II - The Shadow &amp; The Flame (1993)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Brøderbund Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Brøderbund Software, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Redneck Rampage (1997) (+ Suckin' Grits on Route 66 (1998)) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Redneck Rampage</name>
		<image>./images/Redneck Rampage (1997) (+ Suckin' Grits on Route 66 (1998)) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19970430T000000</releasedate>
		<developer></developer>
		<publisher></publisher>
		<genre></genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Redneck Rampage II - Redneck Rampage Rides Again (1998) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Redneck Rampage Rides Again</name>
		<image>./images/Redneck Rampage II - Redneck Rampage Rides Again (1998) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19980531T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Xatrix</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay</publisher>
		<genre></genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rick Dangerous (1989).conf</path>
		<name>Rick Dangerous</name>
		<desc>The plot of Rick Dangerous is largely based on the Indiana Jones movie Raiders of the Lost Ark. Set in 1945, British agent Rick Dangerous travels to the Amazon jungle to search for the lost Goolu tribe. His plane crashes in the jungle, and Rick must escape from the enraged Goolu. When the game starts Rick finds himself in a cave running from a rolling boulder, a famous scene from the Indiana Jones movie.

Armed with a pistol and dynamite, Rick must fight hostiles and evade traps in three more levels. The second level of the game is set inside a pyramid located in Egypt. In the third level, Rick must venture to the Nazi stronghold of Schwarzendumpf castle to rescue captured Allied soldiers. The rescued soldiers tell him that the Nazis are planning a missile attack on London. Therefore, in the last level, Rick must infiltrate their secret missile base.</desc>
		<image>./images/Rick Dangerous (1989)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Core Design</developer>
		<publisher>Rainbird Software</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rick Dangerous II (1990).conf</path>
		<name>Rick Dangerous 2</name>
		<desc>At the end of Rick Dangerous 1, we learn that an alien invasion is imminent. As Rick Dangerous 2 starts, UFOs land in London. The image shift in the character of Rick Dangerous is evident from the start: The coat is nowhere to be found and the Indiana Jones-style hat from the previous episode is almost symbolically blown off by a laser beam coming from one of the spaceships in the introduction sequence. One UFO lands in Hyde Park, and Rick goes there to settle the score with the aliens.</desc>
		<image>./images/Rick Dangerous II (1990)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Core Design</developer>
		<publisher>Micro Style</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sid Meier's Civilization (1991).conf</path>
		<name>Sid Meier's Civilization</name>
		<desc>Sid Meier's Civilization is a turn-based strategy "4X"-type strategy video game created by Sid Meier and Bruce Shelley for MicroProse in 1991.The game's objective is to "Build an empire to stand the test of time": it begins in 4000 BC and the players attempt to expand and develop their empires through the ages from the ancient era until modern and near-future times. It is also known simply as Civilization, or abbreviated to Civ or Civ I.</desc>
		<image>./images/Sid Meier's Civilization (1991)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>MPS Labs</developer>
		<publisher>MicroProse Software, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./SimCity 2000 (1993) (+ Great Disasters (1994) + SCURK (1994)) (SC2000SE) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>SimCity 2000</name>
		<desc>SimCity 2000 is the successor to the city simulation game Sim City. You are once again the mayor, but this time you can fully customize the terrain before building your city. The graphics are isometric, whereas the original had graphics displayed in a top-down fashion.

This title adds numerous features over the original such as the ability of building "light" zones, subways, hospitals, colleges, zoos, and arcos which are actually cities in cities. You can now give names to places, and your city is surrounded by neighboring towns with which you can make trade. Finally, instead of the poll in the first game you now have the option of reading several newspapers to get an idea of your progress.</desc>
		<image>./images/SimCity 2000 (1993) (+ Great Disasters (1994) + SCURK (1994)) (SC2000SE) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Maxis</developer>
		<publisher>Maxis</publisher>
		<genre>Construction and Management Simulation</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./SkyRoads (1993) (+ Xmas Special (1994)).conf</path>
		<name>Skyroads</name>
		<image>./images/SkyRoads (1993) (+ Xmas Special (1994))-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930811T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bluemoon</developer>
		<publisher>Creative Dimensions</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Street Rod (1989) (+ Street Rod SE (2014)) (streetrodonline.com).conf</path>
		<name>Street Rod</name>
		<desc>Year is 1963 and you're one of the hotshots aspiring to be king of the county. You're given a small sum of money to buy your first car. Tune it for maximum performance and off you go. In the diner where other hotshots are waiting to take your prized possession, you race for money and pink slips and if you win, you get to take home their cars! 

The game's interface is relatively easy and fun to use. You have your own garage as the interface itself. Options are in the form of the garage's elements such as the clock for the game's main menu and the newspaper as your source for buying cars and parts. Add to that a third person with an attitude that talks to you as you play It's really a neat idea by which up to now, no other racing games have that style. You feel that you're living a virtual world as opposed to just going from menu to menu. Another realistic part is the ability for you to sell your car and haggle.</desc>
		<image>./images/Street Rod (1989) (+ Street Rod SE (2014)) (streetrodonline.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Magic Partners</developer>
		<publisher>California Dreams</publisher>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Street Rod II - The Next Generation (1991) (streetrodonline.com).conf</path>
		<name>Street Rod 2: The Next Generation</name>
		<desc>Interface is thankfully the same as the first but that's where the similarity ends. More is the name here, more cars and parts to buy giving you every edge to regain your crown. Gameplay is it's most significant thing that you will ever remember in this classic. Gameplay control is really tight.

You're given 3 venues to race your blood thirsty opponent, betting for money and pink slips. The drag race tests how fast you can engage 1st gear.

You're ultimate goal is to beat the new king on these three courses that if you do you get to regain your long lost crown and take home his girl, again.</desc>
		<image>./images/Street Rod II - The Next Generation (1991) (streetrodonline.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Logical Design Works, Inc., P.Z.Karen Co. Development Group</developer>
		<publisher>California Dreams</publisher>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Stunts (1990).conf</path>
		<name>Stunts</name>
		<desc>Stunts (4D Sports Driving outside of US) is a 3D car racing simulation. The game contains a variety of cars, courses, and opponents to choose from. The game provides unusual stunt objects including loops, corkscrews and jumps. It is possible to watch races in instant replay from different camera angles. A track editor is included as well.</desc>
		<image>./images/Stunts (1990)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19901001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Distinctive Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Brøderbund Software, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Racing</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Supaplex (1991).conf</path>
		<name>Supaplex</name>
		<desc>A puzzle game with nice graphics and sound. Reminiscent of Boulder Dash; find the exit while collecting all Infotrons and avoiding the Zonks that can kill you.</desc>
		<image>./images/Supaplex (1991)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Elmer Productions</developer>
		<publisher>Dream Factory</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Syndicate 1993 (1993) (Syndicate Plus) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Syndicate (1993)</name>
		<desc>In the future, the world is controlled by a handful of global corporations (syndicates). You are the Marketing director (hit man) for one of these companies. It is your job to take control away from the competitors. The job is not one of diplomacy, but one of brute force and physical control. Advance your way to the top of the corporation by successfully completing your missions and managing the money you make from your territories.

The gameplay is visually reminiscent of X-Com, with an angled top-down perspective, but it is real time rather than turn based. You have missions ranging from infiltrate and capture, to seek and destroy. In each of these you direct a team of four agents as they move through the world shooting at anything that gets in their way.

You can upgrade and modify your agents, as well as equip them with tools you have researched or liberated from opposing syndicates. As you complete missions, you gain more funds to use for purchasing agents or researching upgrades and equipment.</desc>
		<image>./images/Syndicate 1993 (1993) (Syndicate Plus) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bullfrog Productions</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Syndicate - American Revolt (1993) (Syndicate Plus) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Syndicate: American Revolt</name>
		<desc>American Revolt is an add-on pack to Syndicate. It requires the original game and includes 3 new weapons, 21 new single player missions, and 10 multiplayer missions.</desc>
		<image>./images/Syndicate - American Revolt (1993) (Syndicate Plus) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bullfrog Productions</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The Blues Brothers (1991).conf</path>
		<name>The Blues Brothers</name>
		<desc>The characters have the ability to pick up objects (generally boxes) and either put them down to stand on them, or throw them at enemies. Each level is a variation on the jumping theme, with the characters finding a necessary attribute (e.g. a guitar) somewhere in the level. The sixth and final level ends on-stage.

The game can be played by two players simultaneously, but the scrolling screen only focuses on one of them.

The game's soundtrack consists of music from the movie. Dimitris Yerasimos composed the music for all versions of the game except for Blues Brothers: Jukebox Adventure on Game Boy, where Thorsten Mitschele composed the music.</desc>
		<image>./images/The Blues Brothers (1991)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Titus Software</developer>
		<publisher>Titus Software</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The Blues Brothers II - Jukebox Adventure (1993).conf</path>
		<name>The Blues Brothers II: Jukebox Adventure</name>
		<desc>Jukebox Adventure is the sequel to The Blues Brothers. Once again, the player has to choose a favourite Blues Brother and take him through different side-scrolling platform levels. He needs to collect records and use them as defence by throwing them towards enemies. There are also power-ups that can be gathered until the jukebox to progress to the next level is found.</desc>
		<image>./images/The Blues Brothers II - Jukebox Adventure (1993)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Titus Interactive</developer>
		<publisher>Titus Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The Games - Winter Challenge (1991).conf</path>
		<name>The Games: Winter Challenge</name>
		<desc>An Olympiad game simulating common winter game competitions - the Downhill, Giant Slalom, Luge, 2-men Bobsled, Ski Jump, Cross Country, Biathlon and Speed Skating.

The game features a basic 3D engine which allows to simulate slopes with ease, which enhances the gameplay of some events such as the Downhill. Gameplay, as expected from a Winter sports game, relies on finding the faster trajectories in most events (Downhill, Giant Slalom, Luge and Bobsled), pacing the run correctly (Cross Country and Biathlon), skill and timing (Ski Jump), with button mashing reserved for just one (speed skating). The player (up to ten) can select his (or her) competitor face and nationality from one of 16 possible choices, and by selecting different difficulty settings, different computer controlled athletes take part in the competition along the player.</desc>
		<image>./images/The Games - Winter Challenge (1991)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>MindSpan</developer>
		<publisher>Accolade, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Sports</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The Lost Vikings (1993).conf</path>
		<name>The Lost Vikings</name>
		<desc>Three Vikings, Eric the Swift, Olaf the Stout and Baleog the Fierce, were kidnapped by the alien Tomator, the evil Croutonian ruler, who is collecting unique life forms to display in his gallery. The three Vikings will have to combine their unique skills to defeat Tomator, as well as a vast array of aliens, robots, giant snails, big lizards and more.

The Lost Vikings is a side-scrolling platform puzzle game with a twist. Instead of one character who can jump, run, shoot, collect items, flip switches and so on, there are three different characters, each with his own skills. Eric the Swift can jump, run and bash through walls with his tough helmet. Olaf the Stout has a shield which can block attacks, function as an air glider or as a step to stand on. Baleog the Fierce can shoot things with his arrows (including switches) or kill things with his sword. The player has to use the three Vikings as a team if he wants to get past the increasingly difficult levels and puzzles.

The player controls one Viking at a time, but can switch between them at any point. The Vikings have limited space in their inventory which they can use to keep various items. Each Viking has three health points, and if he loses them all from confrontations with dangers, he dies (some threats kill instantly), and the level must be restarted.</desc>
		<image>./images/The Lost Vikings (1993)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Silicon &amp; Synapse, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay Productions, Inc.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./The Lost Vikings II - Norse by Norsewest (1996).conf</path>
		<name>The Lost Vikings II: Norse by Norsewest</name>
		<desc>Get ready for more nights of masochistic puzzle goodness, because the Lost Vikings need your help once again! The brothers (Erik the Swift, Baleog the Fierce and Olaf the Stout) are trying to get back home and you need to guide them through. Two brand new characters (Fang the Werewolf and Scorch the Dragon) also join the fray. Each character has their own special talents and they must be used in concert if you are to win.</desc>
		<image>./images/The Lost Vikings II - Norse by Norsewest (1996)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Blizzard Entertainment Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>Interplay Entertainment Corp.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Theme Hospital (1997) (gog.com).conf</path>
		<name>Theme Hospital</name>
		<desc>Turn Cures into Cash! 

The world of Theme Hospital is home to dozens of goofy, fictional diseases. Some humans are afflicted with Bloaty Head, causing their noggins to triple in size; others suffer from King Complex, a psychological disorder that infects its victims with the irresistible desire to impersonate Elvis Presley. All of these sick people need help – that’s where you come in.

Theme Hospital tasks you with designing, maintaining, and managing a hi-tech hospital as you service hundreds of ailing patients in an attempt to turn cures into cash. You’ll need to be quick on your feet in order to keep your staff happy and patients healthy. Fail, and your business will collapse. It’s time to find out if you've got what it takes to balance the books and the bedpans.

Design and build a hi-tech hospital. Every stage begins with an empty hospital, leaving it to you to plan out and create a facility to deal with the impending crisis. How many rooms should you dedicate to better your facilities? What about diagnosis and treatment operations? Your strategic decisions will mean the difference between success and failure.

Treat patients suffering from humorous afflictions. In real life, disease isn't a laughing matter. In Theme Hosptial, it’s hilarious. You’ll have to cure sick patients afflicted by dozens of wacky problems, ranging from Hairyitis, a smell-enhancing condition caused by prolonged exposure to the moon, to Spare Ribs, an oddball illness that, as its name suggests, causes those infected to grow additional ribs.

Hire staff members and keep them happy. While a hospital’s purpose is to heal the sick, you’ll need a staff of doctors, nurses, receptionists, and handymen to keep it running in tip-top shape. But just like the sick patients they service, your staff has their own wants and needs (often in the form of better pay), so you’ll have to do your best to keep them happy if you want to keep them on board.</desc>
		<image>./images/Theme Hospital (1997) (gog.com)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19970330T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bullfrog Productions</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Construction and Management Simulation</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ugh! (1992).conf</path>
		<name>Ugh!</name>
		<desc>His girlfriend had always had great expectations and one day, by an incredible chance an apple which has fallen right down our caveman's head creates a thought of an aircraft that he can use to earn money. So he makes the machine and uses it for the transport--for picking the other cave friends up and dropping them to their desired destinations. 

Ugh! is an action game where you must complete 69 levels, riding inside a pedal-powered helicopter to pick up passengers and carry them to their destinations. Each level is made of a series of platforms, with several cave entrances. Cavemen walk out of the caves and loudly announce where they want to go. You have to land your helicopter taxi next to the passenger and wait until he crawls inside (if you land on him, he'll fall into the water at the bottom of the level, although he can still be rescued) and then fly to the cave that he wants to get to. Controlling the vehicle is a bit complicated - you cannot directly fly up or down; instead, you have to keep pedalling to fly up, and cease pedalling when you want to go downwards. Bumping into a wall too hard will cause a game over and force you to restart the level. There is also a time limit for each level. To finish a level, you have to serve a number of customers. 

There are some dinosaur adversaries on certain levels - a pterodactyl which appears unexpectedly and flies across the screen, and a triceratops which becomes agitated when you land near and charges at your taxi. 

As you pedal, you exert energy. To refill your energy so that you can keep pedalling, you can pick up a rock and toss it at a tree, making a fruit drop down. Eat the fruit to get more energy.</desc>
		<image>./images/Ugh! (1992)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>EGOSOFT GmbH</developer>
		<publisher>Play Byte </publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Warcraft II - Beyond the Dark Portal (1996).conf</path>
		<name>Warcraft II: Beyond The Dark Portal</name>
		<desc>Warcraft II: Beyond the Dark Portal is an expansion pack for Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness. After defeating the Orcish Horde and capturing the survivors, the Human Alliance attempts to destroy the Dark Portal. However, whilst they destroy the portal, the rift that joins the Orcs' world of Draenor to Azeroth remains.

The Alliance forces decide to enter the rift to the Orcs' home world to attempt to seal it from the other side.

At the same time, Ner'zhul - Warchief of the Shadow Moon clan, who has seized control of the Orcish hordes of Draenor following Orgrim Doomhammer's departure (and eventual defeat) to Azeroth, plans to send his forces to Azeroth to gather magical artefacts in an attempt to open rifts to other worlds.

Beyond the Dark Portal contains two 12 map campaigns; one for each side, 50 new pud's (maps) and a new tile set for the Orc home world.

It also contains 5 new hero characters for each side that actively participate in several of the new single player missions. In function, they are simply super powered versions of standard units that have different sounds.

There are no new standard units however, which many saw as a disappointment.

The map editor also isn't updated to include any of this expansion's new features, though third party programs exist that can add these features to the editor.</desc>
		<image>./images/Warcraft II - Beyond the Dark Portal (1996)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Cyberlore Studios</developer>
		<publisher>Blizzard Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Warcraft II - Tides of Darkness (1995).conf</path>
		<name>Warcraft II: Tides of Darkness</name>
		<desc>Players must collect resources, and produce buildings and units in order to defeat an opponent in combat on the ground, in the air and in some maps at sea. The more advanced combat units are produced at the same buildings as the basic units but also need the assistance of other buildings, or must be produced at buildings that have prerequisite buildings. The majority of the main screen shows the part of the territory on which the gamer is currently operating, and the minimap can select another location to appear in the larger display. The fog of war completely hides all territory which the gamer's has not explored, and shows only terrain but hides opponents' units and buildings if none of the gamer's units are present.</desc>
		<image>./images/Warcraft II - Tides of Darkness (1995)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19951209T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Blizzard Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Blizzard Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Warcraft - Orcs &amp; Humans (1994).conf</path>
		<name>Warcraft: Orcs &amp; Humans</name>
		<desc>The Orcs originated from another world, where the majority were bloodthirsty warriors driven by strife. However, their Warlocks remained aloof, devoted to the research of magic. The Warlocks noticed a rift between the dimensions and, after many years, opened a small portal to another world. One Warlock explored and found a region, whose Human inhabitants called it "Azeroth", from which the Warlock returned with strange plants as evidence of his discovery.

The Orcs enlarged the portal until they could transport seven warriors, who massacred a Human village. The platoon brought back samples of good food and fine workmanship, and a report that the Humans were defenseless. The Orcs' raiding parties grew larger and bolder, until they assaulted Azeroth's principal castle. However, the Humans had been training warriors of their own, especially the mounted, heavily-armed Knights. These, assisted by Human Sorcerors, gradually forced the Orcs to retreat through the portal, which the Humans had not discovered.

For the next fifteen years, one faction of Orcs demanded that the portal be closed. However a chief of exceptional cunning realized that the Humans, although out-numbered, had prevailed through the use of superior tactics, organization, and by magic. He united the clans, imposed discipline on their army and sought new magics from the Warlocks and Necromancers. Their combined forces were ready to overthrow the Humans.</desc>
		<image>./images/Warcraft - Orcs &amp; Humans (1994)-image.jpg</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19940115T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Blizzard Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Blizzard Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Z (1996) (Renegade).conf</path>
		<name>Z</name>
		<desc>is... a real-time wargame in a totally free environment, unhampered by discrete turns or dull hex grids. A hair-raising race for territory and resources as you attempt to crush your opponent completely before he overpowers you. An intuitive control interface - no need to wade through a large and boring manual, just pick up and play. Super smooth multidirectional scrolling. Twenty challenging levels played over five deadly planets each with a unique terrain ranging from frozen Arctic wastes to nightmarish lands of fire and lava.

Z has... robot soldiers with individual personalities which determine how they react to different situations and how effectively they carry out your orders - will they chicken and run, or march gung-ho into the jaws of hell itself? Six robot types with unique personalities and their own weapons, ranging from humble rifles to machine guns and antitank missile launchers. Robots perform up to 40 different actions, created with an incredible 2000 frames of animation. Eleven types of hardware for your robots to control, from tanks, jeeps and armoured personnel carriers to gattling guns and missile launchers. Many different buildings, including factories, radar and repair installations, to capture and control.

Z gives... you sophisticated computer opponents with many individual styles of play. Fast and frantic multiplayer combat. Battle against another human opponents over serial or modem link or link up to four machines on a network. building factories, radar and repair installations, to capture and control.

Z features... four megabytes of stunning in-game graphics. Earth-shattering explosions with tons of shrapnel and flying debris. Over 30 minutes of humorous video sequences with digital audio. A conditional music system which reflects in real-time the state of the battle. Digitised voices for your robot leaders to report on battlefield activity. Extra features that are automatically enabled on higher specification machines: real-time sprite scaling and rotation and SVGA mode.

Z is... the fastest, funniest, most frantic, feature-packed action-strategy game you'll play this century!</desc>
		<image>./images/Z (1996) (Renegade)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19960701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bitmap Brothers</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Zool (1993).conf</path>
		<name>Zool</name>
		<desc>His name is Zool, and he is a gremlin-like creature from another dimension. He is forced to land on the Earth, but his sole goal is to attain the prestigious ranking of a Ninja. To do that, Zool will have to travel through six worlds, each divided into three stages, defeat his enemies, and prove himself worthy of that title.

Zool is a fast-paced side-scrolling platformer. The protagonist can run, jump, climb walls, and shoot enemies. Power-ups for Zool are scattered across the levels. These include life-spending hearts, smart bombs, shields, more powerful jump-skill and a twin Zool. This "twin" makes imitates the original's motions a few seconds after he performs them.

In the options menu the player can change the difficulty and the game speed (two times), the number of continues, and the background music (rock or funk).</desc>
		<image>./images/Zool (1993)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19920701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Gremlin Graphics Software Ltd.</developer>
		<publisher>Gremlin Graphics Software Ltd.</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Zool II (1994).conf</path>
		<name>Zool 2</name>
		<desc>The sequel to Zool sees him take on the bad guys Mental Block and Krool across 15 levels.

Zool 2 is a platform game where you control the titular "Ninja of the Nth Dimension" (or his girlfriend, Zooz, who can complete each level in a slightly different way) as he rampages through a variety of levels, collecting countless tasty treats, shooting any enemies that he encounters and finding bonuses (there's a variety of special power-ups Zool can find - for example, a bomb that follows him and can be blown up at any time to remove on-screen enemies, or a temporary invulnerability). New to the sequel is Zool's ability to scale walls and his new spinning attacks.

On each level you have to collect a certain amount of the featured fruit within an allocated time limit, and then find the exit across the multi-directionally-scrolling levels. There are lots of hidden areas to see, including a bonus Breakout game starring Zool's pet 2-headed dog.</desc>
		<image>./images/Zool II (1994)-image.jpg</image>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Gremlin</developer>
		<publisher>Gremlin</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players></players>
	</game>
</gameList>
